快过来
Hey! Come here!
马上就来
I'm on my way.
他已经神志不清了  但还是指名要见你
把他带进来
他身上只带了这个...
还有这个
你是来杀我的吗
Are you here to kill me?
我知道这是什么
I know what this is.
很久很久以前
I've seen one before.
我在一个男人身上见过
Many, many years ago.
我们在一个梦中相遇
It belonged to a man I met
而那个梦我已经记不清了
in a half-remembered dream.
那个男人满脑子都是激进的想法
A man possessed of some radical notions.
最强大的寄生虫是什么
What is the most resilient parasite?
是细菌  是病毒
A bacteria? A virus?
还是肠道蠕虫
An intestinal worm?
柯布先生的意思是...
What Mr. Cobb is trying to say
是一个想法
An idea.
顽强无比  感染性极强
Resilient. Highly contagious.
你头脑中一旦形成一个想法
Once an idea has taken hold of the brain,
那就几乎无法抹去
it's almost impossible to eradicate.
只要这个想法完整而被理解
An idea that is fully formed, fully understood,
就会深深根植在那里
that sticks.
在大脑里的某个地方
Right in there somewhere.
而你这样的人就来窃取吗
For someone like you to steal?
对  在梦境中  你的意识会放松警惕
Yes. In the dream state, your conscious defenses are lowered...
如此一来你的想法便极易遭到窃取
and that makes your thoughts vulnerable to theft.
这就叫做盗梦
It's called extraction.
斋藤先生  我们能训练你的潜意识进行自我防御
Mr. Saito, we can train your subconscious to defend itself...
就算最出色的盗梦人也无计可施
from even the most skilled extractor.
你凭什么这么肯定
How can you do that?
因为我就是最出色的盗梦人
Because I am the most skilled extractor.
我知道怎样窥探你的想法并找出你的秘密
I know how to search your mind and find your secrets.
我掌握其中的窍门
I know the tricks.
我能教会你  让你即使在睡着时
And I can teach them to you, so that even when you're asleep...
也绝不会放松警惕
your defense is never down.
听着  如果你要我帮忙
Look, if you want my help,
就得完全信任我  对我毫无保留
you're gonna have to be completely open with me.
我得比你的妻子  你的咨询师
I need to know my way around your thoughts better than your wife...
甚至是任何人  都更了解你的想法
better than your therapist, better than anyone.
如果这是梦  梦里有个藏有你秘密的保险箱
If this is a dream, and you have a safe full of secrets...
我必须知道保险箱里有什么
I need to know what's in that safe.
为此你必须对我完全坦诚
In order for this all to work, you need to completely let me in.
祝你们今晚愉快  先生们
Enjoy your evening, gentlemen,
我会考虑一下你们的提议
as I consider your proposal.
他知道了
He knows.
上面是怎么回事
What's going on up there?
斋藤知道了  他在耍我们
Saito knows. He's playing with us.
无所谓  我能找到它  相信我
Doesn't matter. I can get it here. Trust me.
情报就在保险箱里
The information is in the safe.
我提到秘密时  他下意识地盯着它看
He looked right at it when I mentioned secrets.
她来干什么
What's she doing here?
回房间去吧  这里交给我来处理
Just head back to the room. All right? I'll take care of this.
好吧  你最好处理好  别忘了我们的工作
Okay, make sure you do. We're here to work.
如果我跳下去  还能活下来吗
If I jumped, would I survive?
掉进海里的话也许还有希望
With a clean dive, perhaps.
茉儿  你在这干什么
Mal, what are you doing here?
我以为你会想我
I thought you might be missing me.
你知道我想你
You know that I am.
但我不能再相信你了
But I can't trust you anymore.
那又怎样
So what?
看着像是亚瑟的品味
Looks like Arthur's taste.
其实是这次的目标喜欢战后英国画家的作品
Actually, the subject is partial to postwar British painters.
请坐吧
Please, have a seat.
告诉我
Tell me...
孩子们想我吗
do the children miss me?
想到你无法想象
You can't imagine.
你要做什么
What are you doing?
出去透透新鲜空气
Just getting some fresh air.
坐那别动  茉儿
Stay where you are, Mal.
见鬼
God, damn it.
转过身来
Turn around.
道姆  把枪放下
The gun, Dom.
快点
Please.
把信封交出来  柯布先生
Now the envelope, Mr. Cobb.
是她告诉你的呢  还是你本来就知道
Did she tell you? Or have you known all along?
知道你是来偷东西的  还是我们其实在做梦
That you're here to steal from me, or that we are actually asleep?
告诉我你雇主的名字
I want to know the name of your employer.
你也知道在梦里威胁他没用吧  茉儿
Ah, there's no use threatening him in a dream, right, Mal?
那得看你怎么威胁了
That depends on what you're threatening.
杀了他只会让他醒过来
Killing him would just wake him up.
而疼痛...
But pain...
他的大脑会感受到疼痛
Pain is in the mind.
从周围的布局来看
And judging by the decor,
我们是在你的梦里吧  亚瑟
we're in your mind, aren't we, Arthur?
搞什么  你醒得太早了
What are you doing? It's too soon.
我知道  但梦境崩溃了
I know. But the dream's collapsing.
我尽量让斋藤多逗留一会
I'm gonna try to keep Saito under a little bit longer.
我们快得手了
We're almost there.
他差点就得手了
He was close. Very close.
拦住他
Stop him!
不起作用  把他叫醒
This isn't gonna work. Wake him up.
他醒不过来
He won't wake.
机密
-让他坠落  -什么
- Give him the kick. - What?
把他推下去
Dunk him.
他昏过去了
He's out.
你是有备而来啊
You came prepared, hmm?
连我的保安主管都不知道这座公寓
Not even my head of security knows this apartment.
你怎么会知道
How did you find it?
像你这种地位的男人
It's difficult for a man of your position
要保密这样一个爱巢可不容易
to keep a love nest like this secret...
尤其对方还是有夫之妇
particularly where there's a married woman involved.
-不可能  -但事实摆着  我们在这了
- She would never... - Yet here we are.
-进退两难  -他们慢慢逼近了
- With a dilemma. - They're getting closer.
-你们已经达到目的了  -并没有
- You got what you came for. - Well, that's not true.
你把关键部分藏起来了吧
You left out a key piece of information, didn't you?
你知道我们的目的  所以有所保留
You held something back because you knew what we were up to.
-但你为何还让我们进来  -算是一次试探
- Question is, why'd you let us in at all? - An audition.
-什么试探  -不重要了  你失败了
- An audition for what? - Doesn't matter. You failed.
我们窃取了你脑中所有的情报
We extracted every bit of information you had in there.
但你的诡计已被拆穿了
But your deception was obvious.
放了我  你们走吧
So leave me and go.
你还不明白吗  斋藤先生
You don't seem to understand, Mr. Saito.
雇佣我们的公司  他们可不允许失败
That corporation that hired us, they won't accept failure.
不然我们就死定了
We won't last two days.
柯布
Cobb?
看来我只能简单粗暴一下了
Looks like I'm gonna have to do this a little more simply.
把你知道的告诉我们
Tell us what you know!
快点告诉我们
Tell us what you know, now!
我一直讨厌这条地毯
I've always hated this carpet.
它褪色和磨损得这么与众不同
It's stained and frayed in such distinctive ways.
但好歹是条羊毛毯子
But very definitely made of wool.
可现在...
Right now...
我却躺在一条涤纶毯子上
I'm lying on polyester.
也就是说  我不是躺在自己公寓的地毯上
Which means I'm not lying on my carpet, in my apartment.
你果然不负盛名  柯布先生
You have lived up to your reputation, Mr. Cobb.
我依然在做梦
I'm still dreaming.
-进展如何  -不太妙
- How'd it go? - Not good.
梦中有梦  真是佩服
Dream within a dream, huh? I'm impressed.
但在我梦里  得由我说了算
But in my dream, you play by my rules.
这么说吧  斋藤先生...
Ah, yes, but you see, Mr. Saito...
我们不是在你的梦里
We're not in your dream.
而是在我的梦里
We're in mine.
蠢货  你怎么会把地毯搞错
Asshole. How do you mess up the carpet?
-那不是我的错  -你可是筑梦师
- It wasn't my fault. - You're the architect.
我怎么知道他会把他揍得贴在地毯上
I didn't know he was gonna rub his cheek on it!
别吵了
That's enough.
还有你  你究竟在搞什么
You. What the hell was all that?
-我控制住了局势  -是么  那失控岂不是更夸张
- I have it under control. - I'd hate to see you out of control.
没时间争论了  我要在京都下车
We don't have time for this. I'm getting off at Kyoto.
怎么  他又不会查看每节车厢
Why? He's not gonna check every compartment.
没错  但我不喜欢坐火车
Yeah, well, I don't like trains.
听好  各自保重吧
Listen. Every man for himself.
你好
Yes, hello?
-爸爸  -爸爸
- Hi, Daddy. - Hi, Dad.
小鬼们  你们好吗  过得怎样
Hey, guys. Hey. How are you? How you doing, huh?
-很好  -还好吧
- Good. - Okay, I guess.
还好吧  这是谁在说话  是你吗  詹姆斯
Okay? Who's just okay? Is that you, James?
是我  爸爸  你什么时候回家
Yeah. When are you coming home, Dad?
不行  亲爱的  我不能回家
Well, I can't, sweetheart. I can't.
还得一阵子  记得吗
Not for a while, remember?
为什么
Why?
我说过了  我要工作  不能回家
Look, I told you, I'm away because I'm working, right?
外婆说你再也不会回来了
Grandma says you're never coming back.
菲丽帕  是你吗
Phillipa, is that you?
让外婆听电话好吗
Put Grandma on the phone for me, will you?
她在摇头
She's shaking her head.
那我们只能但愿她错了
Well, just hope she's wrong about that.
爸爸
Daddy?
怎么了  詹姆斯
Yeah, James?
妈妈和你在一起吗
Is Mommy with you?
詹姆斯  我们谈过了
James, we talked about this.
妈妈已经不在这了
Mommy's not here anymore.
那她在哪里
Where?
好了  孩子们  说再见吧
That's enough, kids. Say bye-bye.
听着  我会让外公带些礼物回去  好吗
Listen, I'm gonna send some presents with Grandpa, all right?
你们要听话...
And you be good, you be...
-直升机就在房顶  -好
- Our ride's on the roof. - Right.
你没事吧
Hey, are you okay?
我很好  怎么了
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine. Why?
我们在梦里时  茉儿出现了
Well, down in the dream, Mal showing up.
很抱歉她开枪打了你的腿
Look, I'm, uh, sorry about your leg.
不会再这样了
Won't happen again.
情况越来越糟了吧
It's getting worse, isn't it?
我们就事论事好吧  亚瑟
One apology's all you're getting, all right, Arthur?
-纳什人呢  -他还没来  要等他吗
- Where's Nash? - He hasn't shown. You wanna wait?
我们早该在2小时前就把
We were supposed to deliver Saito's expansion plans...
斋藤的扩建计划交给科博工程公司
to Cobol Engineering two hours ago
现在他们肯定知道我们失败了
By now, they know we failed.
我们得赶快跑路
It's time we disappear.
-你要去哪里  -布宜诺斯艾利斯
- Where you gonna go? - Buenos Aires.
在那里避一阵风头
I can lie low there,
等风平浪静了没准还能揽个活  你呢
maybe sniff out a job when things quiet down. You?
回美国
Stateside.
记得代我问候你家人
Send my regards.
他出卖了你们  跑来求我饶他一命
He sold you out. Thought to come to me and bargain for his life.
现在我交给你们处理吧
So I offer you the satisfaction.
我不做这种事
It's not the way I deal with things.
-你要对他怎么样  -没什么
- What will you do with him? - Nothing.
但科博公司就难说了
But I can't speak for Cobol Engineering.
-你想要我们做什么  -植梦
- What do you want from us? - Inception.
-可能吗  -当然不可能
- Is it possible? - Of course not.
你要是能从别人脑中窃取想法
If you can steal an idea from someone's mind...
为何不能反过来植入一个念头
why can't you plant one there instead?
好吧  现在我来对你植入一个想法
Okay, here's me planting an idea in your head.
我说  "不要去想大象"
I say, "Don't think about elephants".
你会想到什么
What are you thinking about?
大象
Elephants.
没错  但这不是你的想法
Right. But it's not your idea,
因为你知道是我灌输给你的
because you know I gave it to you.
目标的大脑总能追溯想法的来源
The subject's mind can always trace the genesis of the idea.
-不可能假造真实的想法来源  -那不一定
- True inspiration's impossible to fake. - That's not true.
-你能做到吗  -你是在给我选择吗
- Can you do it? - Are you offering me a choice?
因为我自己有办法摆平科博的麻烦
Because I can find my own way to square things with Cobol.
那你自己选择吧
Then you do have a choice.
那我选择离开  先生
Then I choose to leave, sir.
告诉机组你的目的地
Tell the crew where you want to go.
柯布先生
Hey, Mr. Cobb.
如果让你回家  回到美国的孩子身边  意下如何
How would you like to go home,to America, to your children?
这你做不到  没人可以
You can't fix that. No one can.
-比植梦还难吗  -柯布  走吧
- Just like inception. - Cobb, come on.
-这个想法有多复杂  -相当简单
- How complex is the idea? - Simple enough.
你要植入对方大脑中的想法
No idea is simple when you need to plant it
不可能简单
in somebody else's mind.
我的主要竞争对手是个病入膏肓的老人
My main competitor is an old man in poor health.
他的儿子马上就要继承他的公司
His son will soon inherit control of the corporation.
我要他决定解散他父亲的商业帝国
I need him to decide to break up his father's empire.
-柯布  我们不要插手  -先等一下
- Cobb, we should walk away from this. - Hold on.
如果我愿意干  如果我确实做到了
If I were to do this, if I even could do it...
我需要你的保证
I'd need a guarantee.
-我怎么确定你能做到  -你别无选择
- How do I know you can deliver? - You don't.
只能相信我
But I can.
那么你是想心怀幻想
So do you want to take a leap of faith...
还是变成一个老人  心中充满悔恨
or become an old man, filled with regret...
孤零零地等死
waiting to die alone?
集结你的团队吧  柯布先生
Assemble your team, Mr. Cobb.
这次可要慎重挑选队友了
And choose your people more wisely.
我知道你有多想回家
Look, I know how much you wanna go home.
但这活我们干不了
This can't be done.
不  可以
Yes, it can.
只要潜入得足够深
Just have to go deep enough.
你没法确定
You don't know that.
我以前做过
I've done it before.
是对谁
Who'd you do it to?
我们为什么去巴黎
Why are we going to Paris?
我们需要一个新的筑梦师
We're gonna need a new architect.
你从来不喜欢你的办公室吧
You never did like your office, did you?
那个地方小得根本没法思考
No space to think in that broom cupboard.
你来这里安全吗
Is it safe for you to be here?
你也知道  法国和美国间的引渡条款
Extradition between France and the United States...
简直就是官僚主义的噩梦
is a bureaucratic nightmare, you know that.
说不定就你这个案子
I think they might find a way
他们会想办法破个例
to make it work in your case.
我买了一些东西
Look, I, uh, brought these for you to...
你有机会就带给孩子们吧
give to the kids when you have a chance.
时不时地送点绒毛玩具
It'll take more than the occasional stuffed animal...
这样做爸爸可不行
to convince those children they still have a father.
我只是尽我所能
I'm just doing what I know.
这些都是你教我的
I'm doing what you taught me.
我从没教你去偷东西
I never taught you to be a thief.
没错  你教我如何引导别人的思想
No, you taught me to navigate people's minds.
但在那件事以后...
But after what happened...
几乎就没什么合法的机会
there weren't a whole lot of legitimate ways
能让我发挥这种技能了
for me to use that skill.
道姆  你来这做什么
What are you doing here, Dom?
我想我找到回家的方法了
I think I found a way home.
只要为一些权高位重的人干上一票
It's a job for some very, very powerful people.
我相信他们能彻底撤销对我的指控
People who I believe can fix my charges permanently.
但我要你帮忙
But I need your help.
你是来带坏我最好的学生吗
You're here to corrupt one of my brightest and best.
你知道我开的条件优越
You know what I'm offering.
你得让他们自己决定
Let them decide for themselves.
-钱吗  -不仅仅是钱
- Money. - Not just money.
你也知道
You remember.
那会让我们有机会
It's the chance to
建造大教堂和整座城市
build cathedrals, entire cities...
创造那些现实中从未存在过
things that never existed...
也绝不可能存在的事物
things that couldn't exist in the real world.
所以你想要我让其他人
So you want me to let someone else
跟你一起走进你的幻想
follow you into your fantasy?
他们不必亲自进入梦境
They don't actually come into the dream.
他们只需设计梦境
They just design the levels
再把详情教给梦主就行
and teach them to the dreamers. That's all.
你自己设计好了
Design it yourself.
茉儿会阻止我
Mal won't let me.
回到现实中来吧  道姆
Come back to reality, Dom.
-求你了  -现实
- Please. - Reality.
我的孩子  也就是你的外孙...
Those kids, your grandchildren...
正等着他们的父亲回家
they're waiting for their father to come back home.
对他们来说这才是现实
That's their reality.
而只有完成这最后一次任务
And this job, this last job,
我才能实现这个愿望
that's how I get there.
如果不是走投无路  我绝不会来这求你
I would not be standing here if I knew any other way.
我需要个和我一样出色的筑梦师
I need an architect who's as good as I was.
比你更出色
I've got somebody better.
艾莲涅
Ariadne?
这位是柯布先生
I'd like you to meet Mr. Cobb.
很高兴见到你
Pleased to meet you.
如果你有时间
If you have a few moments,
柯布先生有份工作给你
Mr. Cobb has a job offer.
他想和你聊几句
He'd like to discuss with you.
实习吗
A work placement?
也不算
Not exactly.
我要先测试一下你
I have a test for you.
你不先告诉我是什么工作吗
You're not gonna tell me anything first?
在这之前  我得确认你能够胜任
Before I describe the job, I have to know you can do it.
-为什么  -严格来说  这并不合法
- Why? - It's not, strictly speaking, legal.
给你两分钟时间  设计一个
You have two minutes to design a maze
花费一分钟才能解开的迷宫
that it takes one minute to solve.
时间到
Stop.
再试一次
Again.
时间到
Stop.
这都太简单了
You're gonna have to do better than that.
这才像话
That's more like it.
都说我们只开发了大脑真正潜力的一小部分
They say we only use a fraction of our brain's true potential.
但这只是在我们醒着的时候
Now, that's when we're awake.
当睡着时  我们的大脑几乎无所不能
When we're asleep, our mind can do almost anything.
比如呢
Such as?
想象一下  你设计一座建筑物时
Imagine you're designing a building.
你有意识地设计出每个部分
You consciously create each aspect.
但有时却感觉像是建筑在自行构建
But sometimes, it feels like it's almost creating itself,
明白我的意思吗
if you know what I mean.
对  我只需要去发现而已
Yeah, like I'm discovering it.
纯粹的灵感  是吧
Genuine inspiration, right?
而在梦里  大脑会连续地保持这样
Now, in a dream, our mind continuously does this.
创造和感知  这两个过程同步发生
We create and perceive our world simultaneously.
而我们的大脑是如此神奇
And our mind does this so well
以至于我们自己根本没意识到
that we don't even know it's happening.
这么一来我们就能直接进入这个过程
That allows us to get right in the middle of that process.
-怎么做  -由我们来创造
- How? - By taking over the creating part.
这就是你的工作
Now, this is where I need you.
你创造一个梦境
You create the world of the dream.
我们把目标带入这个梦境
We bring the subject into that dream,
这个梦境里则会充满他们的潜意识
and they fill it with their subconscious.
一个梦境的细节要有多逼真
How could I ever acquire enough detail
才能让对方相信自己身处现实
to make them think that it's reality?
我们做梦时总是感觉很真实吧
Well, dreams, they feel real while we're in them, right?
只有等我们醒来后
It's only when we wake up
才会意识到不对劲
that we realize something was actually strange.
问你个问题吧
Let me ask you a question.
你从不记得梦的开头吧
You never really remember the beginning of a dream, do you?
总是突然就这么置身其中
You always wind up right in the middle of what's going on.
我想是吧
I guess, yeah.
那我们是怎么来这的
So how did we end up here?
我们刚从...
Well, we just came from the, uh...
仔细想想  艾莲涅  你怎么来这的
Think about it, Ariadne. How did you get here?
你现在哪里
Where are you right now?
我们在做梦吗
We're dreaming?
你其实正睡在工作坊中央
You're in the middle of the workshop, sleeping.
这是你分享梦境的第一课  冷静
This is your first lesson in shared dreaming. Stay calm.
如果这只是做梦  你为什么要遮挡...
If it's just a dream, then why are you covering...
因为这绝不仅仅只是个梦
Because it's never just a dream, is it?
玻璃刺在脸上的感觉生疼
And a face full of glass hurts like hell.
你做梦时  感觉是真实的
When you're in it, it feels real.
所以军队开发了分享梦境系统
That's why the military developed dream sharing.
士兵能通过这个程序
It was a training program for soldiers to shoot,
身临其境地射击  格斗和搏杀
stab and strangle each other...
而不会受到伤害
and then wake up.
筑梦师的工作是什么
How did architects become involved?
总得有人去设计梦境吧
Well, someone had to design the dreams, right?
再给我们五分钟吧
Why don't you give us another five minutes?
五分钟
Five minutes?
怎么会  我们少说也谈了一个小时
What? We were talking for, like, at least an hour.
你做梦时  大脑运转速度加快
In a dream, your mind functions more quickly...
所以时间相对变慢
therefore time seems to feel more slow.
现实中的五分钟  相当于梦境里的一小时
Five minutes in the real world gives you an hour in the dream.
何不看看你在五分钟内能做些什么
Why don't you see what you can get up to in five minutes?
基本布局有了  书店  咖啡店
You've got the basic layout. Bookstore, cafe?
该有的东西差不多都有了
Almost everything else is here too.
-这些人是谁  -我潜意识中的映射
- Who are the people? - Projections of my subconscious.
-你的吗  -对
- Yours? - Yes.
记住  你是梦主  你创造了梦境
Remember, you are the dreamer. You build this world.
而我是目标  梦境里充满了我的潜意识
I am the subject. My mind populates it.
你还可以和我的潜意识交谈
You can literally talk to my subconscious.
这也是盗取目标秘密的方法之一
That's one of the ways we extract information from the subject.
除此之外呢
How else do you do it?
你可以设计一个安全场所
By creating something secure,
比如银行金库  或是监狱
like a bank vault or a jail.
重要信息就会自动存入其中
The mind automatically fills it with information it's trying to protect.
明白了吗
You understand?
-你再潜入梦境去偷吗  -这个嘛...
- Then you break in and steal it? - Well...
我本以为梦境该基于视觉
I guess I thought that the dream's space should be all about the visual,
但其实更重要的是去感觉
but it's more about the feel of it.
我想知道  如果我颠覆了
My question is what happens when you
物理规律  会有什么后果
start messing with the physics of it all?
-很厉害吧  -是啊
- It's something, isn't it? - Yes, it is.
他们为什么都看着我
Why are they all looking at me?
因为我的潜意识觉得这是别人创造的梦境
Because my subconscious feels that someone else is creating this world.
你改建得越离谱
The more you change things,
映射就会越早如潮水般涌向你
the quicker the projections start to converge on you.
这是什么意思
Converge?
他们一旦察觉外来入侵的梦主
They sensed the foreign nature of the dreamer.
就会像白血球抵抗感染那般攻击对方
They attack like white blood cells fighting an infection.
他们会攻击我们吗
Are they gonna attack us?
不  只攻击你
No, actually, just you.
这样很棒  但我也说了
This is great. But I'm telling you,
如果你再这么继续下去...
if you keep changing things like this...
受不了  就不能让你的潜意识冷静点么
Gees! Mind telling your subconscious to take it easy?
这可是我的潜意识  我自己没法控制
It's my subconscious, remember, I can't control it.
佩服
Very impressive.
我认识这座桥  这是现实中的场所吧
I know this bridge. This place is real, isn't it?
对  我每天穿过桥去学校
Yeah, I cross it everyday to get to the college.
绝不能重建你记忆里的场景
Never recreate places from your memory,
必须创造新的东西
always imagine new places.
你总得借用熟悉的东西吧
Well, you gotta draft from stuff you know, right?
只能借用细节...
Only use details, uh...
比如路灯啊电话亭啊  但绝不能复制整块地方
A street lamp, or a phone booth, never entire areas.
为什么
Why not?
因为借用记忆中的场景塑造梦境
Because building a dream from your memory...
极易让你迷失何为梦境何为现实
is the easiest way to lose your grasp on  what's real and what is a dream.
-你有过这种经历吗  -听着
- Is that what happened to you? - Listen to me,
这和我无关  懂吗
this has nothing to do with me, understand?
所以你要我来帮你筑梦吗
Is that why you need me to build your dreams?
放开她  走开
Get off of her. Back off.
-滚开  -别碰我
- Back off! - No!
别碰她
Get off of her!
茉儿
Mal!
把我叫醒  快把我叫醒
Wake me up! Wake me up!
茉儿
Mal! Mal!
把我叫醒
Wake me up! Wake me up!
看着我  你没事了  没事了
Hey, hey, hey! Look at me. You're okey? You're okey?
为什么我醒不过来
Why... why wouldn't I wake up?
因为设定的时间还没到
Because there was still some time on the clock,
除非你在梦里死去  不然没法提前醒来
and you can't wake up within a dream unless you die.
-她需要个图腾  -什么
- She'll need a totem. - What?
图腾是个小的私人...
A totem is a small personal...
你的潜意识可真厉害啊  柯布
That's some subconscious you've got in you, Cobb.
还是个美人呢
She's a real charmer!
看来你见过柯布夫人了
Oh, I see you met Mrs. Cobb.
-那是他妻子吗  -对  话说图腾...
- She's his wife? - Yeah. So... a totem,
你需要一个小巧的物件
you need a small object potentially heavy,
能够一直带在身边
something could have on you all the time
-不能让别人知道  -像硬币吗
- that no one else knows. - Like a coin?
不  得更独特才行
No, it must be more unique than that.
这是一个注铅的骰子
This is a loaded die.
不  你不能碰  不然就没意义了
No, I can't let you touch it, that would defeat the purpose.
只有我知道这个特制骰子的重心和重量
Only I know the balance and the weight of this particular loaded die.
只有这样  当你看着自己的图腾
That way, when you look at your totem,
你才能确信自己不在别人的梦里
you know, beyond a doubt, that you're not in someone else's dream.
我不知道...
I... I don't know...
你是不想知道还是的确不知道
if you can't see what's going on, or if you just don't want to,
柯布的内心深处隐藏着很严重的问题
but Cobb has some serious problems that he's tried to bury down there.
我可不想对这种人敞开心扉
And I'm not about to just open my mind to someone like that.
她会回来的
She'll be back.
我还从没见过有人能学得这么快
I've never seen anyone pick it up that quickly before.
现实已经不能满足她了
Reality is not gonna be enough for her now.
当她回来时...
When she comes back...
你就教她设计迷宫
when she comes back, you're gonna help her building mazes.
-那你呢  -我要去找伊姆斯
- Where're you gonna be? - I gotta go visit Eames.
伊姆斯  他在蒙巴萨[肯尼亚港口城市]
Eames? Now he's in Mombasa.
那里可是科博公司的老巢
It's Cobol's backyard.
必须冒这个险
It's a necessary risk.
神偷多了去了
There's plenty of good thieves.
我们不仅需要小偷  我们需要个伪装者
We don't just need a thief. We need a forger.
你再怎么搓也生不出钱来
You can rub them together all you want, they're not gonna breed.
那可不一定
You never know.
去喝一杯吧
I'll get you a drink.
你请客
You're buying.
-你的拼写还是这么差  -滚你的
- Your spelling hasn't improved. - Piss off.
-书写怎么样了  -好使着呢
- How's your handwriting? - Versatile.
-那就好  -多谢
- Good. - Thank you very much.
植梦
Inception.
在你费心告诉我这不可能前...
Now, before you bother telling me it's impossible...
这当然可能  只是难得要死
No, it's perfectly possible. It's just bloody difficult.
只是难吗
Just difficult?
亚瑟总说这不可能
Arthur keeps telling me it can't be done.
哈  亚瑟  你还和那个扑克脸在一起么
Hmm... Arthur. You're still working with that stick-in-the-mud?
作为前哨来说他很优秀  是吧
He's good at what he does, right?
是最优秀的  只是缺乏想象力
Oh, the best. He has no imagination.
-你就不同  -听着  如果你要植梦
- Not like you. - Listen, if you wanna perform inception,
-必须要有想象力  -问你个问题
- you need imagination. - Let me ask you something,
-你以前做过吗  -我们试过
- have you done it before? - We tried it.
想法都就位了  但对方没有上钩
We got the idea in place, but it didn't take.
你们植入得不够深吗
You didn't plant it deep enough?
这不只是深度问题
It's not just about depth, you know...
植入的想法必须极其简单
you need the simplest version of the idea,
让目标觉得这是自然而生的想法
in order it to grow naturally in the subject's mind.
这可是相当微妙的艺术
That's a very subtle art.
你要植入的想法是什么
So what is this idea that you need to plant?
我们要让一个大公司的继承人
We need the heir of a major corporation
决定瓦解他父亲的企业帝国
to dissolve his father's empire.
这么说吧  关于反垄断的看法
Well, you see right there, you have various political motivations of...
有各种各样的政治动机  诸如此类
anti-monopolistic sentiments and so forth, and all of that stuff.
但是所有的一切
That's all.
最终还是取决于目标的偏好  明白吗
It's really at the mercy of your subject's prejudice, you see?
你只须着眼于最基本的东西
All you have to do is to start with the absolute basic.
-是什么  -他和父亲之间的关系
- Which is what? - The relationship with the father.
-你有药剂师了吗  -还没有
- Do you have a chemist? - No, not yet.
那好
Alright.
这儿有个人  叫尤瑟夫・皮耶罗
Okey, there's a man here, Yusuf Pierro.
他配制的药剂独一无二
He formulates his own versions of the compounds.
你什么时候带我去见见
When are you taking me there?
你先甩掉跟踪你的人吧
Once you've lost your tail.
吧台边的那家伙
Man at the bar.
科博公司开的赏金
Cobol engineering.
对我的悬赏要求是死是活
That price on my head, was that "dead or alive?"
不记得了  看他开不开枪吧
I don't remember. Let's see if he starts shooting.
你替我引开他  我们半小时后
Run interference, I'll meet you downstairs in the bar in, say uh...
酒吧楼下见吧
say half an hour?
-再回到这里吗  -最危险的地方最安全
- Be back here? - It's the last place they'd expect.
好吧
Hum-hmm. Well...
弗雷迪  你是弗雷迪・赛文斯吗
Freddy, Freddy Savens?
天啊  真的是你吗
My God, it's you, isn't it?
看来我认错人了
No, it isn't.
这下你不是在做梦了吧
You're not dreaming now, are you?
那边
There!
没事
Okey.
咖啡  要一杯咖啡
Oh, uh... cafe. One... one cafe.
一杯咖啡
One cafe.
要搭车么  柯布先生
Care for a lift, Mr. Cobb?
你怎么会在蒙巴萨
What're you doing here in Mombasa?
我得保护我的投资对象
I need to protect my investments.
甩个人就这么难吗
Ahh, so this is your idea of losing a tail, uh?
还有一伙人
Different tail.
柯布说过你会回来
Cobb said you'd be back.
我也不想  但...
I tried not to come. But...
你已经无法自拔了
But there's nothing quite like it.
只是...纯粹的创造
It's just... pure creation.
我们来看一些矛盾建筑吧
Shall we take a look at some paradoxical architecture?
如果你要建造三层不同的梦境
You're gonna have to master a few tricks,
就得掌握一些窍门
if you're gonna build three complete dream levels.
抱歉
Excuse me.
什么样的窍门
What kind of tricks?
在梦里  你可以把建筑设计成不可能图形
In a dream, you can cheat architecture into impossible shapes.
这样你就能造出闭合的循环
That lets you create closed loops,
好比彭罗斯阶梯  无止尽的阶梯
like the Penrose steps, the infinite staircases.
看见了吗
See?
矛盾建筑
Paradox.
这样的闭合循环
So a closed loop like that will help you
有助你分辨梦境的边缘
disguise the boundaries of the dream you create.
梦境的每一层需要多大
But how big do these levels have to be?
随你  一个楼面一幢大楼或是一座城市
It could be anything from the floor of a building to an entire city.
但梦境必须非常复杂
But they have to be complicated
能让我们躲避映射的追踪
enough that we can hide from the projections.
比如一个迷宫吗
A maze?
对  迷宫  迷宫越好...
Right, a maze, and the better the maze...
映射就越难找到我们吗
Then the longer we have before the projections catch us?
-没错  -我的潜意识就很有礼貌
- Exactly. - My subconscious seems polite enough.
等着瞧  他们会翻脸不认人
You wait, they'll turn ugly.
没人喜欢别人在自己的大脑里乱窜
No one likes to feel someone else messing around in their mind.
柯布不能再筑梦了吧
Cobb can't build anymore, can he?
就算他可以  他也不愿意了
I don't know if he can't, but he won't.
他觉得他不知道梦境的话会更保险
He thinks it's safer if he doesn't know the layouts.
为什么
Why?
他不愿意说  我想是因为茉儿吧
He won't tell me. I think it's Mal.
-他前妻吗  -不  不是
- His ex-wife? - No, not his ex.
-他们还在一起吗  -不  她...
- They're still together? - No, she...
她已经死了
she's dead.
你看到的她不过是他脑中的映射
What you just see in there is just his projection of her.
-她在现实中怎么样  -她很迷人
- What was she like in real life? - She was lovely.
-你要找药剂师吗  -对
- You're seeking a chemist? - Yes.
任务需要配制药剂吗
To formulate compounds for a job.
还得和我们一起进入梦境
And to go into the field with us.
不  我从不进入梦境  柯布先生
No, I rarely go into the field, Mr. Cobb.
你得在梦里根据需要定做药剂
We need you there to tailor compounds specific to our needs.
-有什么要求  -足够深度
- Which are? - Great depth.
梦中梦吗  两层梦境
A dream within a dream? two levels?
-三层  -这不可能
- Three. - Not possible.
这种多层梦境太不稳定了
That many dreams within dreams is too unstable.
有可能  只需要加镇静剂
It is possible. You just have to add a sedative.
强效镇静剂
A powerful sedative.
-一共几个人  -五个
- How many team members? - Five.
六个
Six.
只有我和你们一起进入梦境
The only way to know you've done the job
才能确定你是否完成了任务
is if I go in with you.
这种工作可不能带观光客
There's no room for tourists on a job like this,
斋藤先生
Mr. Saito.
那这次得破例了
This time it seems there is.
先试试这个吧  我每天都用
This, I think, is a good place to start. I use it everyday.
-用来做什么  -来  我带你看看
- What for? - Here, I'll show you.
-你得做好心理准备  -你先请
- Perhaps, you will not want to see. - After you.
十个...十二个  全部连在一起
Ten... twelve, all connected.
天啊
Bloody hell!
他们每天来这分享梦境
They come here everyday to share the dream.
看见了吗  非常稳定
You see? Very stable.
-他们每天做梦多久  -三四个小时吧
- How long do they dream for? - Three, four hours, each day.
-梦里是多久  -在这种药效下
- And the dream time? - With this compound?
每人每天四十个小时
About 40 hours, each and every day.
他们为什么这么做
Why do they do it?
你来说吧  柯布先生
Tell him, Mr. Cobb.
在你用药一阵子后
After a while,
不用药就没法做梦了
it becomes the only way you can dream.
你还做梦吗  柯布先生
Do you still dream, Mr. Cobb?
他们每天来这做梦吗
They come here everyday to sleep?
不  他们是为了醒过来
No, they come to be woken up.
梦境已成了他们的现实  谁又能说不是呢
The dream has become their reality. Who are you to say otherwise, uh?
让我见识一下吧
Let's see what you can do.
你知道怎么找到我  你知道你该怎么做
You know how to find me. You know what you have to do.
很鲜明吧
Sharp? No?
你没事吧  柯布先生
Are you all right, Mr. Cobb?
放心  我没事
Yeah, yeah. I'm just fine.
罗伯特・费舍
Robert Fischer,
费舍明日能源集团的继承人
heir to the Fischer-Morrow Energy Conglomerate.
你和这位费舍先生有何瓜葛
What's your problem with this Mr. Fischer?
这不关你的事
That's not your concern.
斋藤先生  这...
Mr. Saito, this...
这可不是一般的商业间谍活动
this isn't your typical corporate espionage.
你让我植梦  我希望你明白...
You asked me for inception, I do hope you understand that...
这其中的严重性
the gravity of that request.
我们会在对方脑中植入一个想法
The seed that we plant in this man's mind will grow into an idea.
这个想法会决定他的行为
This idea would define him. It may come to change...
可能会彻底改变他的人生
it may come to change everything about him.
我们是仅存的能和他们抗衡的能源公司
We're the last company standing between them and total energy dominance.
但我们快撑不住了
We can no longer compete.
很快他们将控制半个世界的能源供给
Soon they'll control the energy supply of half the world.
事实上  他们将成为新兴超级帝国
In effect, they become a new superpower.
全世界都需要罗伯特・费舍
The world needs Robert Fischer
改变主意
to change his mind.
这要看我们的了
That's where we come in.
罗伯特・费舍
How is Robert Fischer's
和他父亲的关系如何
relationship with his father?
传言他们之间的关系有些复杂
Rumor is their relationship is quite complicated.
但光靠传言可不够  是吧
But we can't work based solely on rumor, can we?
你能让我接近这个男人吗
Can you get me access to this man here,
布朗宁
Browning?
老费舍的左膀右臂
Fischer senior's right-hand man,
小费舍的教父
Fischer junior's godfather.
应该不难  只要你有合适的推荐信
It should be possible, if you can get the right references.
搞推荐信可是我的专长  斋藤先生
References are something of a speciality for me, Mr. Saito.
这里还有未解决的事项
I'm not smelling settlement here.
-去搞定它  -布朗宁先生
- Take them down. - Mr. Browning,
莫里斯・费舍的原则之一
Maurice Fischer's policy is always one of
就是避免一切诉讼
avoiding litigation.
那我们是不是应该把你的想法
Well, shall we voice your concerns
直接告诉莫里斯
with Maurice directly?
没那个必要吧
Not sure if that's necessary.
不  我觉得有必要
No, no, no. I think we should.
他怎么样了
How is he?
我也不想因琐事而麻烦他  但...
I don't wanna bother him unnecessarily, but...
罗伯特  我告诉过你
Robert, I've told you to
别让那些该死的...
keep out the damn...
照做就是了
Just do it!
你不适合讲话  费舍先生
No, don't speak, Mr. Fischer.
总是不照我说的做
Never... never do thing what I asked.
出去吧
Leave town.
这一定是他宝贵的回忆
Must be a cherished memory of this.
我把相框放在他床边  他甚至都没注意到
I put it beside his bed. He hasn't even noticed it.
罗伯特  我们得谈谈委托书的问题了
Robert, we need to talk about the power of attorney.
我知道现在不合适...
I know this is hard for you...
现在不行  彼得叔叔
Not now, uncle Peter.
但刻不容缓  我们得开始...
But it's imperative that we start to...
秃鹰在盘旋
The vultures are circling.
莫里斯・费舍病得越重
It is the sicker Maurice Fischer becomes,
彼得・布朗宁就越强大
The more powerful Peter Browning becomes.
我充分观察了布朗宁
I've had ample opportunity to observe Browning,
记下了他的模样  行为模式和习惯等等
adopt his physical presence, study his mannerisms, so on and so forth.
所以在梦境的第一层
So now, in the first layer of the dream,
我可以模仿布朗宁
I can impersonate Browning,
并给费舍的大脑灌输暗示
and suggest the concept to Fischer's conscious mind.
当我们带他进入更深一层
Then, when we take him a level deeper,
他脑中产生的布朗宁的映射
his own projection of Browning should...
会把这些信息反馈给他自己
should feed that right back to him.
-让他觉得这是自己的想法  -没错
- So he gives himself the idea? - Precisely.
只能这么做  必须是自发生成的想法
That's the only way it will stick. It has to seem self-generated.
伊姆斯  不错嘛
Eames, I am impressed.
能得到你的赞赏
Your condescension, as always,
我真是受宠若惊  亚瑟  感激不尽
is much appreciated, Arthur. Thank you.
你一个人进入梦境吗
Were you going under on your own?
不  我就是做些实验
No, no. I was just, uh...  just running some experiments.
没想到这里还有人  所以...
I didn't realize anyone was here. So...
嗯  其实我在弄我的图腾
Yeah, I was just... I was working on my totem, actually.
给我看看
Here, let me take a look.
你学得还真快
So you're learning, huh?
这种鉴别现实的方法好优雅啊
An elegant solution for keeping track of reality.
-是你的主意吗  -不  其实...
- Was it your idea? - No, it was, uh...
其实是茉儿的主意  这个...
It was Mal's, actually. This is...
这个陀螺以前是她的
This one was hers.
陀螺在梦里转起来就不会倒
She'd spin it in a dream and it would never topple,
就这么一直转下去
just spin and spin.
听亚瑟说她去世了
Arthur told me she passed away.
迷宫设计得怎么样了
How are the mazes coming along?
梦境的每一层都和我们
Each level relates to the part of the subject's
要了解的目标潜意识有关
subconscious that we're trying to access, so...
所以最后一层设计成医院
Making the bottom level hospital,
这样费舍就会见到他父亲...
so Fischer will bring his father, um...
其实关于这层我有个疑问
You know, actually I have a question about this layout...
不不不  不要告诉我细节
No, no, no. Don't... don't show me the specifics.
只有梦主才能知道细节
Only the dreamer should know the layout.
为什么这么在意这点
Why's that so important?
以防我们中有人带入了自己的映射
In case one of us brings in our projections,
可不能让映射知道迷宫的细节
we don't want them knowing the details of the maze.
你是说茉儿吗
You mean in case you bring Mal in?
你没法控制她吧
You can't keep her out, can you?
-对  -你之所以不能筑梦
- Right. - You can't build them because...
因为只要你知道迷宫布局  她也就知道了
if you know the maze, then she knows it.
她就会破坏整个行动
She'd sabotage the whole operation.
柯布  其他人知道吗
Cobb, did the others know?
不  不知道
No, they don't.
如果情况恶化  你得警告他们
You gotta warn them if this is getting worse.
谁说会恶化了
No one said it's getting worse!
我必须回家
I need to get home.
我现在只关心这点
That's all I care about right now.
你为什么不能回家
Why can't you go home?
因为警察认为我杀害了她
Because they think I killed her.
-谢谢  -谢什么
- Thank you. - For what?
没有问我是不是真的杀了她
For not asking whether I did.
"我要瓦解我父亲的帝国"
"I will split up my father's empire."
显然这个想法
Now this is obviously
会被罗伯特立刻拒绝
an idea that Robert himself would choose to reject.
所以我们得把这个想法
Just why we need to plant it
植入他潜意识深处
deep in his subconscious.
潜意识由感性激发  而不是理性吧
Subconscious is motivated by emotion, right? Not reason.
我们得设法把这转化为感性因素
We need to find a way to translate this into an emotional concept.
怎么把一个商业策略转变成感性因素
How do you translate a business strategy into an emotion?
这不等着我们想办法么
That's what we have to figure out, right?
而罗伯特与他父亲的关系紧张
Now, Robert's relationship with his father is stressed,
费舍家族两代人之间的战争
甚至更糟
to say the least.
你看这样如何
Can we run with that,
我们暗示他  让他认为解散公司
we could suggest to him breaking up his
是对自己老子的一次反抗
father's company as a "screw you" to the old man?
不行
No,
因为积极情感总是胜过消极情感
'cause I think positive emotion trumps negative emotion every time.
我们的心理追求协调  需要宣泄
We all yearn for reconciliation, a catharsis.
必须让罗伯特・费舍
We need Robert Fischer
对整件事产生积极的情感
to have a positive emotional reaction to all this.
好吧  试试这个...
Alright, well, try this, um...
"我父亲希望我自己创业"
"my father accepts that I want to create for myself,
"而不是跟随他亦步亦趋"
not follow in his footsteps."
-有点意思  -有点
- That might work. - Might?
光是"有点"可不行
We need to do a little better than "might".
多谢你的建议  亚瑟
Oh, thank you for your contribution, Arthur.
明确点总没错吧  明确"一"点
Forgive me for wanting a little specificities. Specificity?
植梦可不能指望明确  我们在他的意识里
Inception is not about being specific. When we get inside his mind,
只能随机应变
we're gonna have to work with what we find.
在第一层梦境  我们先拿父子俩的关系开刀
On the top level, we open up his relationship with his father,
告诉他  "我不想再追随父亲的脚步"
say, "I will not follow in my father's footsteps."
到了第二层  我们让他产生这样的想法
Then the next level down, we feed him,
"我要创造自己的事业"
"I will create something for myself."
最后在第三层  我们就亮出王牌
Then, by the time we hit the bottom level, we bring out the big guns...
-"我父亲不想我变成他"  -没错
- "my father doesn't want me to be him. - Exactly.
三层梦境很不稳定  稍有干扰
With three layers down, the dreams are gonna collapse...
梦境就会崩溃
with the slightest disturbance.
用镇静剂让你入睡...
Sedation, for a sleep...
这样足够稳定  可以维持三层梦境
stable enough to create three layers of dreaming.
我们得加入相当强效的镇静剂
We have to combine with an extremely powerful sedative.
晚安
Good night.
我们分享梦境时使用的药剂
The compound we'll be using to share the dream
让每个人间的联结变得异常清晰
creates very clear connection between dreamers,
同时也会加快大脑运转速度
whilst actually accelerating brain function.
换句话说  每层梦境的时间会增加
In other words, it gives us more time on each level.
大脑功率在梦中是正常状态下的二十倍
Brain function in the dream will be about twenty times normal.
而当你进入更深一层  时间会加倍
When you enter a dream within that dream, the effect is compounded.
三层梦境  也就是十小时乘以二十...
Three dreams, that's ten hour times twenty...
不好意思
I'm sorry, uh...
我数学向来不好
math's never my strong subject.
-究竟是多长时间  -第一层是一周
- How much time is that? - It's a week the first level down.
第二层是半年  而第三层则是...
Six months the second level down. And the third level...
十年
Ten years.
谁愿意困在梦里十年之久
Who would wanna be stuck in a dream for ten years?
看是什么梦咯
Depends on the dream.
那么完成任务后  我们要怎么回来
So once we've made the plant, how do we get out?
巴望着你这回能优雅些
I'm hoping you have something more
不用一枪把我的头打爆
elegant in mind than shooting me in the head?
-用坠落  -什么叫坠落
- A kick.- What's a kick?
看这儿  艾莲涅  这就叫坠落
This, Ariadne, would be a kick.
是一种强烈的下坠感  将你震醒
It's that feeling of falling, you get the jolts to wake.
进而把你拖离梦境
It snaps you out of the dream.
用那种强力镇静剂  我们能感觉到坠落吗
Are we gonna feel a kick with this kind of sedation?
妙就妙在这儿
Oh, that's the clever part.
在这种镇静剂中
I customize the sedative
我特意保留了内耳功能的完整
to leave inner ear function unimpaired.
这样一来  无论你睡得多沉  都能感到下坠
That way, however deep the sleep, the sleeper still feels falling,
或倾倒
or tipping.
关键是  要让三层梦境的坠落同步发生
The trick is to synchronize a kick that can penetrate all three levels.
我们可以用音乐倒计时为信号
We can use a musical countdown
来同步不同层的坠落
to synchronize different kicks.
他没有手术安排  不看牙医  什么都没有
He hasn't any surgery schedule, no dental, nothing.
他不是该动个膝盖手术吗
Wasn't he supposed to have a knee operation?
没有  没机会让他睡过去  我们...
Nothing. Nothing they'd put him under for, anyway. We need...
我们至少需要十小时
We need at least a good ten hours.
悉尼到洛杉矶
Sydney to Los Angeles,
全世界飞行时间最长的航线之一
One of the longest flights in the world.
他每两周要往返一次
He makes it every two weeks.
那肯定也是坐他的私人飞机
And he must be flying private.
要是私人飞机出故障就坐不成了吧
Not if there were unexpected maintenance with his plane.
-那也得是波音747  -为什么
- It'd have to be a 747.- Why is that?
因为波音747的驾驶舱在最上面
Cause on a 747, pilots are up top,
头等舱在最前部
And the first class cabin's in the nose,
所以没有人会走来走去
So no one would walk through.
但你得包下整个头等舱
But you'd have to buyout the entire cabin,
还要买通头等舱的所有空乘
And the first class flight attendant.
我买下了那家航空公司
I bought the airline.
应该会方便些吧
It seemed neater.
看来十小时不成问题咯
It looks like we have our ten hours.
艾莲涅  那啥  干得漂亮
Ariadne? Terrific work, by the way.
你知道怎么找到我
You know how to find me.
你知道你该怎么做
You know what you have to do.
记得你向我求婚那时吗
You remember when you asked me to marry you?
-我当然记得  -你说你做了个梦
- Of course I do.- You said you had a dream.
-梦到我们白头偕老  -我们可以的
- That we grow old together.- And we can.
你不该来这里
You shouldn't be in here.
我只是想看看
I just want to see what kind of
你每晚都在独自做什么"实验"
"tests" you're doing on your own every night.
不管是什么  都跟你没关系
Whatever it was, it has nothing to do with you.
和我太有关系了
It has everything to do with me.
-你让我和你分享梦境  -不是这些梦
- You've asked me to share dreams with you.- Not these.
这些是我自己的梦
These are my dreams.
你为什么要这么做
Why do you do this to yourself?
只有这样我才能继续做梦
This is the only way I can still dream.
为什么必须得做梦
Why is it so important to dream?
因为在梦里  我们仍能在一起
In my dreams we're still together.
这些不仅是梦  这是你的回忆
These aren't just dreams. These are memories.
-你说过不能用回忆造梦  -我知道
- And you said never to use memories.- I know I did.
你想尽办法让她活着  你放不下她
You're trying to keep her alive.you can't let her go.
你不明白
You don't understand.
这些都是让我追悔不已的瞬间
These are moments I regret,
是我必须改变的记忆
the memories that I have to change.
那这下面有什么让你后悔的事
Well, what's down there that you regret?
听好  对于我  你只用了解一件事
Listen, there's only one thing you need to understand about me.
-这是你家吗  -对  是我和茉儿的家
- This is your house? - Mine and Mal's, yes.
-她人呢  -她已经不在了
- Where is she?  - She's already gone.
那是我儿子詹姆斯
It's my son, James.
他在挖着什么  大概是条虫子
He's digging for something, maybe a worm.
那是菲丽帕
That's Philippa.
你知道吗  我当时想喊他们
You see, I thought about calling out to them,
让他们转过头来对我笑  我就能看到...
so they'd turn and smile and I can see those...
他们俩可爱的面孔  但...一切都太晚了
Those beautiful faces of theirs.but... It's all too late.
再不走就来不及了  柯布
Right now, or never, Cobb.
那时我真的慌了
Then I start to panic.
我知道我不想为此后悔  我...
I realize I don't wanna regret this moment, that I..
我要最后再看一眼他们的面孔
I need to see their faces one last time.
詹姆斯  菲丽帕  快过来
James! Philippa! Come on in!
但我错过了
But the moment's passed.
我再怎么努力都无法改变
Whatever I do I can't change this moment.
就在我想喊他们时  他们跑开了
When I'm about to call out to them, they run away.
我要想再见到他们  就一定得回家
If I'm ever gonna see their faces again, I've gotta get back home,
在现实中相见
In the real world.
-你来这干什么  -我是...
- What are you doing here?  - My name is...
我知道你是谁  你来这干什么
I know who you are.  What are you doing here?
-我只是想试着理解  -你怎么可能理解
- I'm just trying to understand.- How could you understand?
你知道成为彼此的爱人
Do you know what it is to be a lover?
-成为彼此另一半的感觉吗  -不知道
- To be half of a whole?  - No.
来猜个谜语吧
I'll tell you a riddle.
你在等待一列火车  那列火车将载你远去
You're waiting for a train, a train that will take you far away.
你了然自己心向何方
You know where you hope this train will take you,
却不知自己会被载往何处
But you don't know for sure.
但这并不重要
But it doesn't matter.
火车将载你去哪怎会不重要呢
How can it not matter to you where that train will take you?
因为我们会在一起
Because you'll be together.
你怎么能带她来这  道姆
How could you bring her here, Dom?
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这是我们庆祝结婚纪念日的套房
This is a hotel suite where we spent our anniversary.
这里发生过什么
What happened here?
你向我承诺过  我们会在一起
You promised! you promised we'd be together!
求你了  留在这  暂时先留在这
Please, I need you stay here, just for now.
你说过我们会在一起  白头偕老
You said we'd be together! you said we'd grow old together!
我会回来找你  我保证
I'll come back for you, I promise.
你觉得建起一座记忆监狱  就能关住她吗
Do you think you can just build a prison of memories to lock her in?
你真的觉得这样能锁住她吗
Do you really think that's gonna contain her?
是时候了  莫里斯・费舍刚在悉尼去世
It's time.Maurice Fischer just died in Sydney.
-葬礼在哪天  -星期四  在洛杉矶
- When's the funeral? - Thursday, in Los Angeles.
罗伯特应该在周二前护送遗体回去
Robert should accompany the body no later than Tuesday.
我们该行动了
We should move.
-好  -柯布  我跟你一起去
- Right. - Cobb, I'm coming with you.
我答应过迈尔斯  不行
I promised Miles. No.
得有人了解你潜意识里的挣扎
The team needs someone who understands what you're struggling with.
不带上我也可以
And it doesn't have to be me,
但你得把我刚才看见的都告诉亚瑟
but then you have to show Arthur what I just saw.
在飞机上加个位子
Get us another seat on the plane.
如果我上了这飞机  你却不履行我们的协议
If I get on this plane, and you don't honor our agreement,
那着陆后  我就会在监狱里度过余生
When we land, I go to jail for the rest of my life.
在途中完成任务  我只要在飞机上打个电话
Complete the job en route, I make one phone call from the plane,
就能让你顺利入境
You'll have no trouble getting through immigration.
-抱歉  借过  -不好意思
- I'm sorry. - Oh, yeah. I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉打扰了  这是你的吧  肯定是弄掉了
Excuse me, I think this is yours?  You must've dropped it.
-先生们想要喝点什么吗  -来杯水  谢谢
- Would you gentlemen care for a drink?  - Oh, water, please.
一样  谢谢
Same, please.
那个...谢谢
Umm... thank you.
那个  我忍不住看了一眼  你...
You know, I couldn't help but notice, but...
你不会恰巧和那位莫里斯・费舍是亲戚吧
You wouldn't happen to be related to "the Maurice Fischer", will you?
是的  他...他是我父亲
Yes, he, um... he was my father.
他是个很了不起的人  请你节哀顺变
He was a very inspiring figure. I'm sorry for your loss.
-给  -谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
来  敬你父亲  愿他安息
Hey, to your father. May he rest in peace.
-你睡前就不能去解个手么  -抱歉
- Couldn't you have peed before you went under. - Sorry.
免费香槟没少喝吧  尤瑟夫
Bit too much free champagne before takeoff, Yusuf?
呵呵  真他妈好笑
Aha, bloody ha.
这样的天气  他肯定在找出租车
Well now, he's gonna be looking for a taxi in this weather.
-蠢货  你丫怎么不...  -滚
- Asshole! Hey man, why don't you try... - Walk away.
我得挂了  出租车  谢谢
I gotta go. Taxi! Thank you.
好  太好了
Alright...Snappy!
-你干嘛  -抱歉  我以为是空车
- What're you doing?  - I'm sorry. I thought it was free.
-不  有人了  -拼个车吧
- No, it's not. - Maybe we could share.
还是不了  你能不能靠边停下让他...
Maybe not. Can you pull over to get this...
这下好了
Great.
快点
Come on.
这里有五百美元
There's five hundred dollars in there,
这钱包还不止这个价
And the wallet's worth more than that.
-好歹送我到目的地吧  -恐怕...
- So you might at least drop me at my stop.  - I'm afraid...
-掩护他  -不  不  不
- Covering him!  - No! no! no!
这什么情况
What was going on?
我可没设计这个
This wasn't in the design.
柯布
Cobb. Cobb?
干掉他
Get him!
-你没事吧  -没事  我没事  我还好
- Are you alright? - Yeah, I'm alright, I'm okey. I'm okey.
-费舍也没事  没准有点晕车  -斋藤
- Fischer's okey. Unless he gets carsick. - Saito?
把费舍带到里屋去  快点
Get Fischer in the back room, now.
-把他带去里屋  快  -这是怎么回事
- Get him in the back room. Move! - What the hell?
-他中枪了吗  他会死吗  -我不知道
- Has he been shot? Is he dying? - I don't know.
老天呐
Jesus Christ!
你们去哪儿了  发生了什么事
Where were you? what happened to you?
我们被一列货运火车截住了
We were blocked by a freight train.
你干嘛在闹市的十字路口上
Why would you put a train crossing in
放一列火车
The middle of a downtown intersection?
-我没有  -那是哪儿来的
- I didn't.- Where did it come from?
我还要问你呢  我们怎么会遭伏击  说啊
Lemme ask you a question! Why the hell we were ambushed, huh?
那些绝不是普通的映射
Those were not normal projections.
见鬼的他是受过训练的好不好
He'd been trained, for god's sakes!
-你说的没错  -他怎么会受过训练
- You're right.- How could he be trained?
费舍曾让盗梦人训练过他的潜意识
Fischer's had an extractor teach his subconscious
进行自我防御  所以...
to defend itself. so...
他的潜意识经过武装  我早该做好调查
His subconscious is militarized. This should have shown in the research.
-抱歉  -那你他妈怎么没查出来
- I'm sorry.- Why the hell you didn't?
-冷静点  -冷你妹
- Calm down. - Don't tell me to calm down!
这是你分内的事  你他妈要负全责
This was your job, goddamnit! This was your responsibility!
你应该彻查费舍的背景
You were meant to check Fischer's background thoroughly!
我们可没准备好应付这种枪战
We are not prepared for this type of fire!
我们之前处理过潜意识防卫情况
We have dealt with the subsecurity before.
只要小心一点就会没事
We'll be a little more careful.we're gonna be fine.
之前可没有过这种情况  他快死了  见鬼的
"Before" is not a part of the plan! He's dying, for god's sake!
-那就帮他脱离苦海  -别  千万别
- Let's put him out of his misery. - Don't do that! Don't do that!
他太痛苦了  我唤醒他而已
He's in agony. I'm waking him up.
别  那样唤不醒他
No, it won't wake him up.
-唤不醒是啥意思  -那样唤不醒他
- What do you mean, it won't wake him up? - It won't wake him up.
在梦中死去  我们就会醒来
When we die in a dream, we wake up.
这次不行
Not from this.
我们用的镇静剂太强了  那样根本醒不过来
We're too heavily sedated to wake up that way.
好吧  那我们死了会怎样
Right. so what happens when we die?
-坠入迷失域  -开什么玩笑
- Drop into limbo. - Are you serious?
-什么迷失域  -原始的梦境
- Limbo?  - Unconstructed dream space.
那下面都有什么
What the hell is down there?
只有无尽的原始潜意识
Just raw infinite subconscious.
什么都没有
Nothing is down there,
除非与你分享梦境的某人
except for whatever might have been left behind
曾被困在那里  并在那里留下过什么
by anyone sharing the dream who's been trapped there before,
我们这里就只有你去过
Which in our case is just you.
我们会被困在那里多久
But how long could we be stuck there?
在镇静剂消退前  不可能逃得出来
Not even think about trying to escape until the sedation eases...
到底是多久
How long?
也许几十年  也许永远  我也不知道
Decades, it could be infinite, I don't know.
问他  就他去过那儿
Ask him. he's the one who's been there.
先把他抬楼上去再说
Let's just get him upstairs.
好极了  多亏了你啊
Great. Thank you.
我们现在被困在费舍的大脑里
So, now we are trapped in Fischer's mind
和他的私人武装军队搏命
battling his own private army.
要是不小心翘了
And if we get killed,
就会跌进迷失域
we'll be lost in limbo
干等着脑子变成一锅浆糊  是吧
till our brains turn to scrambled egg. hmm?
有急救箱吗
You got first aid?
你知道其中的风险  却没有告诉我们
So you knew about these risks. You didn't tell us?
本来不会有任何风险
There wasn't meant to be any risk.
我怎么知道要面对如此激烈的枪战
I didn't know we'd be dealing with a load of gunfire.
你没权利这么做
You had no right.
只有这样我们才能深入三层梦境
This is the only way to go three layers deep.
还有你  你明知危险  为什么不吱声
And you, you knew about this and went along with it?
我相信他啊
I trusted him.
是吗  就因为他答应分你一半钱吗
You trusted him? When? When he promised you half his share?
不是  他说全给我
No, his whole share.
而且他说他原来干过
Besides, he said he had done it before.
干过  和茉儿那次吗
You had done it before? What? With Mal?
-那次什么下场  -那次和现在没关系
- Cause that works so good? - That has nothing to do with it.
我只是竭尽所能回到我的孩子身边
I did what I had to do to get back to my children.
那你就带我们走上绝路吗
So you led us into a war zone with no way out?
这不是绝路   好吗
There's a way out, alright?
我们继续按计划行事  速战速决
We continue on with the job, and we do this as fast as possible,
然后靠坠落醒过来  和计划没差
And we get out using the kick, just like before.
歇菜吧  越深入风险越大
Forget it. If we go any deeper, we just raise the stakes.
我就在这层  坐等着醒来  又会怎样
I am sitting this one hour on this level, worse?
我们说话这会功夫
Fischer's security is surrounding this place
费舍的潜意识卫队就把这里包围了
Fischer's security is surrounding this place as we speak.
十小时的航线  在这一层就是一星期
The ten hours of flight time is a week at this level.
我可以肯定  要是待在这我们全都死定了
That means each and every one of us will be killed, that I can guarantee.
我们除了速战速决  别无选择
We have no other choice but to continue on and do it as fast as possible.
往下深入才是唯一的出路
Downwards, is the only way forwards.
准备好  你跟我来
Get ready. You, come on.
我们去震他一下
Let's go shake him up.
我为防绑架投了一千万保险
I'm insured against kidnaping for up to ten million.
所以简单行事吧
This should be very simple.
闭嘴  没那么简单
Shut up! It won't be.
你爸办公室的书架下  有个他的私人保险箱
In your father's office, below the bookshelves, is his personal safe.
-我们要密码  -我不知道有什么保险箱
- We need the combination. - I don't know any safe.
那不代表你不知道密码  快告诉我们
It doesn't mean you don't know the combination. Tell us what it is.
我真不知道
I don't know.
我们有可靠来源说你知道
We have it on good authority you do know.
是吗  是谁
Yeah? Who's this authority?
-这玩意居然值五百美元  -打开看看
- Five hundred dollars this cost. - Open inside.
现金  各种卡  身份证  还有这个
Cash, cards, ID, and this.
-有用吗  -也许吧
- Useful? - Maybe.
-靠你了  给你一小时  -就一小时
- You're on. you've got an hour. - An hour?
我本该有整晚时间来对付他
I was supposed to have all night to crack this.
斋藤的胸口本不该中枪子儿
Saito wasn't supposed to be shot in the chest.
一小时  挖出点有用的  拜托
Got one hour to get something useful, please.
什么声音
What's that?
可靠来源呗
Good authority.
彼得叔叔
Uncle Peter.
-先让他们住手  -密码是多少
- Just... just make them stop. - The combination?
-我真不知道  -那为什么布朗宁说你知道
- I don't know it.- What does Browning say you do.
我不知道  让...让我跟他谈谈
I don't know. Just lemme... lemme talk to him,
看是怎么回事
and I'll find out.
给你一小时  谈吧
You have one hour. Start talking.
你还好吧
Are you okey?
这帮杂种已经关了我两天了
Those bastards've had me for two days.
他们派人潜入了你爸的办公室
They have someone with access to your father's office.
-试图打开他的保险箱  -我知道
- And they're trying to open his safe.- Yeah.
他们觉得我知道密码  但我不知道
They thought I'd know the combination, but I don't know it.
-是啊  我也不知  所以...  -什么
- Yeah, well, neither do I. so... - What?
莫里斯告诉我  在他死后
Maurice told me that when he passed,
只有你能打开它
you are the only one to be able to open it.
没有...他从没告诉过我什么密码
No, he never... he never gave me any combination.
也许他说过  我是说
Maybe he did, I mean,
也许你只是不知道那是密码
maybe you just didn't know it was a combination.
-那会是什么  -我不知道
- Well, what then? - I don't know.
你和莫里斯的一些共同经历中
Some meaningful combination of numbers based on your...
那些有意义的数字组合
your experiences with Maurice.
我们没什么...有意义的共同经历
We didn't have very many, um... meaningful experiences together.
或许  在你妈妈去世后
Perhaps, after your mother died.
我妈去世后  你知道他跟我说什么吗
After my mother died, you know what he told me?
"罗伯特  我跟你真没什么好说的"
"Robert, there's really nothing to be said."
别较真  他不善表达情感
Oh, he was bad with emotions.
我当时才十一岁啊  彼得叔叔
I was eleven, uncle peter.
-他怎么样  -疼得不行
- How's he doing? - He's in a lot of pain.
等我们到下面几层  疼痛感就会减弱
When we get down to the lower levels, the pain will be less intense.
-他要是死了呢  -最坏的情况吗
- And if he dies? - The worst case scenario?
他醒来后  会完全迷失了神智
When he wakes up, his mind is completely gone.
柯布  我仍会履行我们的协议
Cobb, I'll still honor the arrangement.
我很感激  斋藤  但...
I appreciate that, Saito. But..
你醒来后  不会记得我们曾有过协议
When you wake up, you won't even remember that we had an arrangement.
你会将迷失域当做现实
Limbo's gonna become your reality.
你会迷失在里面
You're gonna be lost down there so
直到变成一个老人
long that you're gonna become an old man.
-心中充满悔恨  -孤零零地等死
- Filled with regret. - Waiting to die alone?
不  我会回来  我们会一起重回年轻
No, I'll come back. and we'll be young men, together again.
深呼吸
Breathe.
如果我们不交出密码
These people are gonna kill us here,
这伙人会马上杀了我们
if we don't give them the combination.
-他们不过是想要钱  -我听到他们说了
- They just want a ransom. - I heard them.
他们会把我们打晕了塞进货车  再开进河里去
They're gonna whack us in that van and then drive it into the river.
好吧  那保险箱里到底有什么
Alright, what is it in the safe?
是给你的东西
Something for you.
莫里斯总说  那是他留给你最珍贵的礼物
Maurice always said it was his most precious gift to you.
-一份遗嘱  -莫里斯的遗嘱已经交给了律师
- A will.  - Maurice's will is with Port and Dunn.
这份是候补遗嘱
That's an alternate.
如果你愿意  完全可以推翻前一份
This would supersede the other, if you want it to.
这份遗嘱是要解散费舍明日能源集团
It splits up the component businesses of Fischer-Morrow,
这么一来  费舍帝国将土崩瓦解
and it'd be the end of the entire empire as we know it.
不留给我一丝一毫吗
Destroy my whole inheritance?
-他为什么要我这么做  -我也不知道
- Why would he suggest such a thing? - I just don't know.
他爱你  罗伯特  以他独特的方式
He loved you, Robert, in his own way.
他独特的方式吗
In his own way?
他临终前  把我叫到他床前
At the end, he called me to his deathbed.
他连说话都很困难了
He could barely speak.
却仍耗尽最后一口气  告诉我一件事
But he took the trouble to tell me one last thing.
他把我拉近
He pulled me close.
我只勉强听清了一个词
And I could only make out one word --
"失望"
"disappointed."
你什么时候进过迷失域
When were you in limbo?
你或许成功说服了其他人继续任务
You might have the rest of the team convinced to carry on with this job,
-但他们不知道真相  -真相  什么真相
- But they don't know the truth? - Truth? What truth?
真相就是  你随时都有可能
The truth that at any minute,
凭空造出一列货运火车来
you might bring a freight train through the wall.
真相就是  你无法控制你潜意识里的茉儿
The truth that Mal is bursting through your subconscious.
真相就是  我们不断深入费舍意识的同时
And the truth that as we go deeper into Fischer,
也在不断深入你的意识
We're also going deeper into you.
而且  我想大家不会乐于见到真相
And I'm not sure we're gonna like what we find.
我们曾一起工作
We were working together.
努力探索着梦中梦的概念
We were exploring the concept of a dream within a dream.
我费劲功夫向前走  想要走得更深
I kept pushing things. I wanted to go deeper and deeper.
走得更远
I wanted to go further.
我当时还没意识到
I just didn't understand the concept
现实的几小时会变成梦中的几年
that hours could turn into years down there,
而我们陷得如此之深
And we could get trapped so deep that only
醒来时已经到了潜意识的边缘
wound up on the shore of our own subconscious.
我们已经无法分辨梦境和现实
We lost sight of what was real.
我们为自己创造了一个世界
We created and built a world for ourselves.
我们建了很多年
We did that for years.
建起了属于我们自己的世界
We built our own world.
-你们被困了多久  -大概有五十年吧
- How long were you stuck there? - Something like fifty years.
天呐  你们怎么能受得了
Jeez. How could you stand it?
一开始还不错  感觉自己像上帝一样
It wasn't so bad at first, feeling like gods.
问题是这些都不是真的
The problem was none of them was real.
到头来  我终于无法忍受下去
Eventually, it just became impossible for me to live like that.
那她怎么想
And what about for her?
她把某些东西锁进了内心深处
She had locked something away, something deep inside her.
她曾经知晓的现实
The truth that she had once known,
她却选择将其遗忘
but she chose to forget.
她把迷失域当成了现实
Limbo became her reality.
你们醒来后怎么样了
What happened when you woke up?
过了这么多年后再醒来
Well, to wake up from that after... after years, after decades,
苍老的灵魂重新回到年轻的躯体
We come old souls thrown back into youth like that.
我知道她有点不对劲
I knew something was wrong with her.
只是她自己不愿承认
she just wouldn't admit it.
她最终告诉了我真相
Eventually, she told me the truth.
她一直挥之不去一个想法
She was possessed by an idea.
这个微不足道的想法却改变了一切
This one very simple idea that changed everything,
那便是我们的世界不是真的
That our world wasn't real,
她必须醒过来回到现实世界
That she needed to wake up to come back to reality, that...
为此  我们必须自杀
In order to get back home, we had to kill ourselves.
那你们的孩子呢
What about your children?
她认为他们只是潜意识的映射
she thought they were projections,
我们真正的孩子正在现实中等着我们
That our real children were waiting for us up there somewhere.
-我是孩子的妈妈  -冷静点
- I am their mother. - Calm down.
难道我看不出其中的区别吗
Don't you think I can't tell the difference?
如果我在做梦  为什么我无法控制
If this is my dream, why can't I control this?
因为你不知道自己在做梦
Because you don't know you're dreaming!
她是如此坚决  不管我好说歹说
She was certain there was nothing I can do,
我怎么恳求  都无济于事
No matter how much I begged, no matter how much I pleaded.
她想回去  但她又不想一个人走
She wanted to do it, but she could not do it alone.
她太爱我了  所以...
She loved me too much, so...
在我们结婚纪念日那天  她想出个计划
She came up with the plan on our anniversary.
-亲爱的  你在干什么  -一起来吧
- Sweetheart, what are you doing? - Join me.
你先退回屋里  好吗
Just... just step back inside. Alright?
退回屋里  求你了
Just step back inside. now, come on.
不
No.
我要跳了  你要和我一起跳
I'm going to jump. And you are coming with me.
不  我不会跳
No, I'm not.
现在你听我说
Now... now you listen to me.
如果你跳下去  你不会醒来  明白吗
If you jump, you're not gonna wake up. Remember?
而是会死  所以退回屋里去好吗
You're gonna die. now just... just step back inside.
求你了
Come on!
回到屋里  我们好好谈谈
Step back inside so we can talk about this.
我们谈得够多了
we've talked enough.
茉儿
Mal.
你快跨出来  不然我现在就跳下去
Come out onto the ledge, or I'll jump right now.
好
Okey.
我们好好谈谈  好吗
Let's talk about this. Alright?
-我要你心存信仰  -不  亲爱的
- I'm asking you to take a leap of faith. - No, honey,
我做不到  你知道我做不到
I can't. you know I can't do that.
再想想我们的孩子
Take a second to think about our children.
想想詹姆斯  想想菲丽帕
Think about James, think about Phillipa, now.
如果你不和我一起跳  孩子还是会被带走
If I go without you, they'll take them away, anyway.
-什么意思  -我找律师留下了一封信
- What does that mean? - I filed a letter with our attorney,
信中说到我担心自己的安全
explaining how I'm fearful for my safety,
你是如何威胁要杀了我
How you threatened to kill me.
-你为什么这么做  -我爱你  道姆
- why did you do this? - I love you, Dom.
你为什么这么对我
Why did you... why... why would you do this to me?
这样你就不会因离开孩子而内疚
Freed you from the guilt of choosing to leave them.
我们要回真正的家和孩子团聚了
We are going home, to our real children.
不不不  茉儿  听我说  好吗
No, no... no. Mal, you listen to me, alright?
茉儿  看着我  求你了
Mal, look at me, please!
你在等待一列火车
you're waiting for a train,
茉儿  见鬼的  别这样
Mal, goddamnit! Don't do this!
那列火车将载你远去
a train that will take you far away.
詹姆斯和菲丽帕在等你回去
James and Phillipa are waiting for you!
你了然自己心向何方
You know where you hope this train will take you,
-他们在等我们  -却不知自己会被载往何处
- They're waiting for us! - But you don't know for sure.
-茉儿  看着我  -但这并不重要
- Mal, look at me! - But it doesn't matter,
-茉儿  该死  -因为我们会在一起
- Mal, goddamnit! - Because we'll be together.
亲爱的  看着我
Sweetheart! Look at me!
茉儿  不要  老天爷啊
Mal! No! Jesus Christ!
她找了三个心理医生  证明她心智正常
She had herself declared sane by three different psychiatrists,
我根本没法解释
That made it impossible for me to
她的内心有多疯狂
Try to explain the nature of her madness.
所以就这样了
So they're in.
再不走就来不及了  柯布
Right now, or never, Cobb.
好吧  我们走
Fine, let's go.
我丢下了我的孩子
I left my children behind,
自那以后我就一直努力设法回去
And I've been trying to buy my way back ever since.
你的内疚感塑造了她  她才如此强大
Your guilt defines her, it's what powers her.
但是她的想法害死了她  这和你无关
But you are not responsible for the idea that destroyed her.
如果我们这次要成功
And if we're gonna succeed in this,
你必须原谅自己
you have to forgive yourself,
坦然面对内心的她
And you're gonna have to confront her.
但你不用孤身奋战
But you don't have to do that alone.
不  你不能...
No, you don't...
我这是为了其他人
I'm doing it for the others.
因为他们完全不知道
Because they have no idea of the risk
和你一起深入梦境有多危险
they've taken coming down here with you.
我们得走了
We have to move.
-时间到了  -好吧
- Time's up. - All right.
我不知道什么密码  反正清醒时是不知道
I don't know any combination, not consciously anyway.
那直觉呢
How about instinctively, huh?
我们有人正在你父亲的办公室里
I've got somebody standing in your father's office.
现在我们就要输入密码
Right now, we need to tap in the combination.
说出你一下子想到的六位数字
We need the first six numbers that come to your head right now.
-我不知道  -快说
- I have no idea. - Right now!
我让你快说  你说不说
I said right now! Right now!
528  491
5...2...8...491.
这可不对
You'd have to do better than that.
好了  把他们蒙起来
Alright, bag them.
我们开车出去兜一圈
We're going for a ride.
让我们活着更有价值
We're worth much more to you alive...
听到了吗
You hear me?
你有什么收获
What did you get?
他们父子间的关系比我们想象的还糟
That boy's relationship with his father is even worse than we imagined.
这有什么用
This helps us how?
问题越大就越需要宣泄
The stronger the issues, the more powerfully cathartic.
你要怎么协调这么恶劣的关系
How are you gonna reconcile them of so estranged?
-我不正在想嘛  -给我动作快点
- Well, I'm working on that, an't I? - Move fast.
他的映射正快速包围我们
The projections are closing in quick.
我们得赶快突围
we gotta break out of here,
不然就出不去了
Before we're totally boxed in.
真见鬼
Damn it!
亲爱的  怕什么  做梦就得做开点儿
You mustn't be afraid to dream a little bigger, darling.
我们得把他对父亲的怨恨
Now, we need to shift his animosity
转移到他的教父身上
from his father to his godfather.
你要毁了他们这么好的关系吗
Would this destroy his one positive relationship?
不用
No,
我们一边修复父子间的关系
We'll repair his relationship with his
一边揭露他邪恶教父的真面目
father by exposing his godfather's true nature.
真是  比起斋藤  费舍该付我们更多钱
Hell, we should charge Fischer much more than Saito.
那怎么对付他的潜意识映射
What about his security?
我们越深入梦境情况就越糟
It's gonna get worse as we go deeper.
我们可以用查尔斯先生那招
Now, I think we run with Mr. Charles.
不行
No.
-查尔斯先生是谁  -馊主意
- Who's Mr. Charles? - Bad idea.
在第二层  只要我们一接近费舍
The second we get into that hotel and approach fischer,
他的潜意识就会蜂拥而至
His security's gonna be all over us.
我们可以用查尔斯先生那招
We run with Mr. Charles
就像上次斯坦那个活儿一样
like we did on the Stein Job.
-这么说你们做过  -对  但失败了
- So you've done it before? - Yeah, it didn't work.
目标意识到了他在做梦
The subject realized that he was dreaming,
而他的潜意识将我们撕成了碎片
And his subconscious tore us to pieces.
好极了  吃一堑长一智嘛
Excellent. but you've learnt a lot, right?
-得有人分散目标注意力  -没问题
- I need some kind of distraction. - No problem.
我之前用过的那位靓女怎么样
How about a lovely lady I've used before.
-听好了  你小心开车  -好
- Listen to me. you drive carefully, alright? - Yeah.
下一层梦境会相当不稳定
The thing down there's gonna be unstable as hell.
别跳得太早
Don't jump too soon.
我们只有一次坠落机会
We only have one shot at that kick you're gonna make.
我会放音乐提前通知你们
I'll play the music, then you'll know it's coming.
其他的只能靠你们自己了
the rest is on you.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Are you ready? - Ready!
好梦
Sweet dreams!
我让你感到无聊了吗
Am I boring you?
我一直在讲我的故事  但你好像不喜欢
I was telling you my story. I guess it wasn't your liking.
我心里很乱
Oh, um... I have a lot in my mind.
查尔斯先生出场了
There goes Mr. Charles.
你是费舍先生吧
Mr. Fischer? Right?
很高兴再次见到你  我是营销部的罗德・格林
Pleasure to see you again. Rod Green from marketing.
-而你是...  -我是要走了
- And you must be...? - Leaving.
你无聊了就找我吧
In case you get bored...
她一定是把你甩了
Must have blown you off.
除非她的号码真只有六位数
That is unless her phone number, really is only six digits.
这么乱搭讪陌生人
Funny way down, make friends,
很容易被顺手牵羊
someone stealing their wallet like that.
见鬼  光那钱包就值...
Ha, goddamnit! Wallet alone is worth at least...
五百美元吗
About 500 dollars, right?
不用担心  现在我的人已经去处理了
Listen, don't worry about it. My people are already on it as we speak.
查尔斯先生到底是什么意思
Who or what is Mr. Charles?
这招是用来诱使费舍对抗自己的潜意识
It's a gambit designed to turn Fischer against his own subconscious.
那你为什么不赞成
Then why don't you approve?
因为这就得告诉目标他在做梦
'cause it involves telling the mark that he's dreaming,
这样的话就会招来映射的注意
Which involves attracting a lot of attention on us.
柯布不是说绝不能这么做吗
Didn't cobb say never to do that?
你也注意到了吧  柯布口口声声的禁忌
So now you've noticed how much time
他自己却一犯再犯
Cobb spends doing things he says never to do.
斋藤先生  能打扰一下么
Mr. Saito, can I have a moment?
不好意思
Oh, I... I'm sorry.
等等
Wait!
-你看起来气色好多了  -兴致真好  伊姆斯先生
- You look a bit perkier. - Very amusing, Mr. Eames.
飞机遇到气流了吗
Turbulence on the plane?
不  更近一些  是尤瑟夫在开车
No, it's much closer. It's Yusuf's driving.
-不好意思  你刚说你是谁  -营销部的罗德・格林
- I'm sorry, who did you say you were? - Rod Green from marketing.
其实这不是真的吧
That's not true at all, is it?
我的名字是查尔斯  你还记得我吧
My name is Mr. Charles. You remember me, don't you?
我是你在这的安全主管
I'm the head of your security down here.
到其他楼层下电梯  一直走别停下
Get out on a different floor and keep moving.
-扔了钱包  映射会过来找  -好
- Dump the wallet. The security will look for that. - Okey.
我们得为柯布多争取点时间
We need to buy cobb a little more time.
保安啊
Security, huh?
-你为这间酒店工作吗  -不是
- You work for the hotel? - No, no.
我专门负责特殊领域的安全
I specialize in a very specific type of security,
潜意识安全
subconscious security.
你是在说梦吗
Are you talking about dreams?
你是在说盗梦
Are you talking about, um... extraction?
我是来这保护你
I'm here to protect you.
费舍先生  我是来保护你
Mr. Fischer, I'm here to protect you
保护你不被拖入梦境入侵意识
In the event that someone tries access to your mind through your dreams.
你在这不安全  他们冲着你来了
You are not safe here. They are coming for you.
天气很诡异吧
Strange weather, isn't it?
你感觉到了吗
You feel that?
怎么回事
What's happening?
柯布正设法让费舍注意梦中的异常
Cobb's drawing Fischer's attention to the strangeness of the dream,
所以他的潜意识开始寻找梦主了
which is making his subconscious look for the dreamer,
也就是我  快吻我
For me. Quick, give me a kiss.
-他们还是盯着我们  -没错  不过这也值了
- They're still looking at us. - Yeah, it's worth a shot.
我们还是离开这吧
We should probably get out of here.
你感觉到了吗
Do you feel that?
费舍先生  其实你受过训练
You've actually been trained for this, Mr. Fischer.
注意天气的反常和重力的转移
Pay attention to the strangeness of the weather, the shift of the gravity.
这一切都不是真的  你在做梦
None of this is real. You're in a dream.
最简单的证明方法  就是设法回想一下
Now, the easiest way for you to test yourself is to try to remember,
你如何来到这家酒店  行吗
How you arrived at this hotel. Can you do that?
好  但我...
Year, I don't, I...
放松  呼吸  仔细回想你受过的训练
Now, breathe, breathe. Remember your training,
接受你在做梦的事实  我是来保护你的
Accept the fact that you're in the dream, and I'm here to protect you.
继续想想
Go on.
-你不是真人吗  -对  我不是
- You're not real? - No, no.
我是你潜意识里的映射
I'm a projection of your subconscious.
我是来保护你
I was sent here to protect you in the event
防止盗梦人将你拖入梦中
that the extractors try to pull you into a dream.
费舍先生  我肯定他们正在动手
And I believe that's what's going on right now, Mr. Fischer.
好吧
Yeah, okey.
好的
Okey.
-你能带我离开这吗  -当然  跟我来
- Can you get me out of here? - Right away. Follow me.
这算什么  你做了什么
This is what? What're you doing?
他们是被派来绑架你的  明白吗
These men were sent here  to abduct you, alright?
如果你要我帮忙  就得保持冷静
If you want my help, you have to remain calm.
费舍先生  你得和我合作
I need you to work with me, Mr. Fischer.
如果这是梦  我只要自杀就能醒过来吧
If this is a dream, I should just kill myself to wake up. Right?
费舍先生  换做我就不会这么做
I wouldn't do that if I were you, mr. fischer.
我肯定他们对你用了镇静剂
I believe that they have you sedated.
如果你扣动扳机  就醒不过来了
If... if you pull that trigger, you may not wake up.
你会坠入更深层的梦里
You may go into a further dream state now.
你明白我在说什么
You know what I'm talking about.
回想下你受过的训练和我对你说的话
You remember the training. Remember what I said to you.
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
-这房间在528房间正下方吧  -没错
- This room should be directly below 528? - Yeah.
好好想想  费舍先生
Think, Mr. Fischer, think.
回想下做梦前发生了什么
What do you remember from before this dream?
好像发生了很激烈的枪战...
Oh... there was, um... there was a lot of gunfires.
还下着大雨...
There was... rain.
彼得叔叔
Uncle peter.
-天呐  我们被绑架了  -你们被关在哪里
- Oh my god, we've been kidnaped. - Where were they holding you?
-我们被关在一辆货车后面  -难怪重力会转移
- They had us in the back of a van. - That explains the gravity shifts.
你们正在一辆货车后面  再好好想想
You're in the back of a van right now. Ke...keep going!
好像...和一个保险箱有关
It had something to do with, um... something to do with a... a safe.
天呐  怎么这么难回想
God, why is it so hard to remember?
就像你醒来试图回想自己的梦一样
It's like trying to remember a dream after you've woken up.
这需要长时间的练习
Listen to this, it takes years of practice.
你和布朗宁被拖进了这个梦境
You and Browning have been pulled into this dream,
因为他们想从你的头脑中窃取某样东西
Because they're trying to steal something from your mind.
我要你集中精神  努力回想下那是什么
I need you to focus and try to remember what that is.
到底是什么  好好想想  费舍先生
What is it, Mr. Fischer? Think!
是一组密码
Uh... a combination.
他们要我说出一下子想到的几个数字
They demanded the first numbers that popped into my head.
他们试图从你的意识里窃取数字
They were trying to extract the number from your subconscious.
这可能代表任何东西  我们现在酒店里
It can represent anything. We are in a hotel right now.
也许是房间号码  那组数字是什么  费舍先生
Should try hotel rooms. What was the number, Mr. Fischer?
快努力回想下  这很重要
Try and remember for me. This is very important.
5...52...这串数字很长
5...52... it was something long number...
已经很好了
That's good enough.
我们先试试看
We could start there.
-是五楼  -好
- Fifth floor. - Yep.
-你准备用计时器吗  -不  我得自己判断
- So do you use a timer? - No, I have to judge it for myself.
你们在528房间做梦时
While you're all asleep in 528.
我等着尤瑟夫的坠落信号
I wait for Yusuf's kick.
-你怎么知道  -他会放音乐提醒我
- Well, how will you know? - His music warns me.
到时货车会撞上桥边的护栏
And then when the van hits the barrier of the bridge,
这点清楚无误  我们就能完美地同步坠落
That should be unmistakable. So we get a nice, synchronized kick.
如果炸得太早  我们没法回到上层
If it's too soon, we won't get pulled out.
如果炸得太晚  我们也无法坠落
And if it's too late, I won't be able to drop this.
-为什么  -因为到时货车是自由下落
- Why not? - Because of the van that will be in free fall.
-失重情况下掉不下来  -也是
- Can't drop you without gravity. - Right.
我们是一起的
They're with me.
-查尔斯先生  -费舍先生
- Mr. Charles. - Do you know
你知道这是什么吗
what that is, Mr. Fischer?
我想我知道
Yeah, I... I think so. yeah.
他们想把你拖入梦里
They were trying to put you under.
-我已经在梦里了  -再拖入更深一层
- I'm already under. - Under again.
什么意思  梦里还能做梦吗
What do you mean? A... Dream within a dream?
-哎呀  你换了身行头  -不好意思  你是哪位
- Hey, I see you've changed. - I'm sorry?
抱歉  我把你当成了我的一个朋友
Oh... I'm sorry. I've mistaken you for a friend.
你那朋友一定很帅
Good looking fella, I'm sure.
那是费舍潜意识里映射出的布朗宁
That's fischer's projection of browning.
我们跟着他  看他做什么
Let's follow him and see how he behaves.
-为什么  -这样我们就能知道
- Why? - Because how he acts would tell us...
费舍是否如我们设计般怀疑布朗宁
If Fischer's starting to suspect his motives as the way we wanted to.
-彼得叔叔  -你不是说你们被一起绑架的吗
- Uncle peter? - You said you were kidnaped together?
也不是
Well, um... well, not... not exactly.
他们先抓了他  还一直在拷问他
They... they already had him.they were torturing him.
你亲眼看到他们拷问他了吗
And you saw them torture him?
那些绑匪是你的人
The kidnapers are working for you?
罗伯特...
Oh, Robert...
你要打开保险箱  拿那份候补遗嘱吗
You're trying to get that safe open? So you get the alternate will?
费舍明日公司是我一生的心血
Fischer-Morrow has been my entire life.
我不能让你毁掉它
I can't let you destroy it.
我怎么会亲手毁掉自己的遗产呢
I'm not gonna throw away my inheritance! Why would I?
我不忍让你看到你父亲最后的嘲弄
I couldn't let you rise to your father's last taunt.
什么嘲弄
What taunt?
就是那份遗嘱  罗伯特
The will, Robert.
就是他对你莫大的侮辱
That will, that's his last insult, a challenge for you...
让你冒险去自己创造财富
you'd build something for yourself,
认为你不配继承他的成就
by telling you you're not worthy of his accomplishments.
-他的确对我很失望  -我很抱歉
- Well, that he was, um... disappointed. - Hmm, I'm sorry.
但是他错了
But... he's wrong.
你完全能超越他的成就
You can build a better company than he ever did.
-费舍先生  他在说谎  -你怎么知道
- Mr. Fischer, he's lying. - How do you know?
相信我  我就是干这行的
Trust me, it's what I do.
他有什么瞒着你
He's hiding something,
我们得找出真相
And we need to find out what that is.
我要你以其人之道还治其人之身
I need you to do the same thing to him that he was going to do to you.
我们要进入他的潜意识
We'll enter his subconscious and
找出他内心隐藏的秘密
find out what he doesn't want you to know.
好
All right.
他睡过去了
He's out.
等等  我们到底要进入谁的潜意识
Wait, whose subconscious are we going into exactly?
费舍的潜意识
We're going into Fischer's.
我告诉他是进入布朗宁的潜意识
But I told him it was Browning's,
这样他就会协助我们
so he can be a part of our team.
他会帮助我们侵入自己的潜意识
He's gonna help us break into his own subconscious.
没错
That's right.
映射会追着你四处跑吧
The security's gonna run you down, huh?
看本少爷让他们疲于奔命
Then I will lead them on a merry chase.
记得赶在坠落前回来
Just be back before the kick.
好好睡吧  伊姆斯先生
Go to sleep, Mr. Eames.
你没事吧
Are you good?
-喂  你准备好了吗  -没事  我准备好了
- Hey! Are you ready? - Yes, yes, I'm... I'm fine. I'm ready.
柯布  那里面会有什么
Cobb. cobb? What's down there?
我们希望费舍了解的真相
Hopefully the truth we want Fischer to learn.
我是指你的潜意识里会有什么
I mean, what's down there for you?
你们看到了吗
Huh... did you see that?
伊姆斯  这是你的梦境
Eames, this is your dream.
我要你引开医院里的警卫  明白吗
I need you to draw the security away from the complex. Do you understand?
-那谁带费舍进去  -我不行
- Who will guide Fischer in? - Not me.
我如果知道了路线  会危及整个任务
If I know the route, everything could be compromised.
-这是我设计的迷宫  -不  你得跟着我
- I... I designed the place. - No, you're with me.
-我能行  -好吧
- I can do it. - Alright.
跟他简单说下前往医院的路线
You brief him on the route into the complex.
费舍  你跟着他走
Fischer, you'll be going with him.
好  你呢
Alright. What about you?
保持线路畅通  我会一直监听
Keep this live. I'll be listening in the whole time.
建筑上层的窗户都很宽敞
The windows on that upper floor're big
我可以在南面的塔楼上掩护你
enough for me to cover you from that south tower.
-看见了吗  -好  你不进去吗
- You see it? - Yeah. you're not coming in?
你要了解关于你父亲的真相
In order to find out the truth about your father,
就得自己潜入布朗宁的潜意识
you're gonna need to break into Browning's mind on your own.
走吧  费舍
Come, Fischer!
拉警报  拉警报
Sound the alarm! Sound the alarm!
行动
Move!
快上
Go!
但愿你们准备好了
Hope you're ready.
不  太早了
No, it's too soon.
柯布  听见了吗
Cobb, do you hear that?
二十分钟前就有动静  我还以为是风声
First heard it about twenty minutes ago. I thought it was the wind up here.
我听见了  是音乐
Yeah, I hear it. It's music.
-那怎么办  -抓紧时间
- So what do we do? - Move fast!
尤瑟夫还有十秒就跳了
Yusuf's ten seconds for the jump,
也就是说亚瑟还有三分钟
which gives Arthur three minutes.
-我们有多少时间  -六十分钟
- Which gives us what? - Sixty minutes.
他们能在一小时内赶到那吗
Can they make that route in under an hour?
他们还得下到中层平台上
They still have to climb down to the middle terrace.
必须换条路线  找条捷径
Well, then they need a new route, a more direct route.
在那
There!
我可是照迷宫设计的
It's designed as a labyrinth.
迷宫里也能有近道吧
There must be access routes that cut through the maze, right?
伊姆斯
Eames.
-伊姆斯有改动过吗  -你还是不知道为好
- Did Eames add any features? - I don't think I should tell you.
-要是茉儿知道了...  -没时间了
- If Mal finds out... - We don't have time for this.
他改动过吗
Did he add any?
他加了套通风系统  通过这可以抄近道
He added an airduct system that can cut through the maze.
好极了  告诉他们
Good, explain it to them.
-斋藤  -说
- Saito? - Go ahead?
-死路一条  -不
- Paradox. - No...!
-怎么回事  -是坠落
- What was that? - The kick.
-柯布  我们错过了吗  -错过了
- Cobb! Cobb, did we miss it? - Yeah, we missed it.
丫的就不能在梦里造个海滩吗
Couldn't someone have dreamt up a goddamned beach, huh?
-现在怎么办  -在下次坠落前完成任务
- What the hell do we do now? - We finish the job before the next kick.
-哪还有坠落  -货车坠入水中的瞬间
- What next kick? - When the van hits the water.
如需拨打电话  请先挂机重试
If you want to make a call, please hang up and try again.
失重情况下该如何让你们坠落
How can I drop you without gravity?
亚瑟还有几分钟  我们大概有二十分钟
Arthur has a couple of minutes, we have about twenty.
你没事吧
Are you okey?
快走  回基地去
Move on! To the base!
有点不对劲  警卫好像发现了什么
There's something wrong, they're heading your way,
朝你们那边去了
like they know something.
多拖延些时间  好吗  走吧
Just buy us some more time, alright? Come on!
这就去
On my way.
那就是保险库外的前厅
That's the antechamber outside the strong room.
保险库有窗户吗
Does the strong room have windows?
要是有就不保险了
Well, I mean it wouldn't be very strong if it did.
但愿费舍喜欢我们的设计
Let's hope Fischer likes what he finds in there.
-这些映射是他的潜意识吗  -对
- Are those projections part of his subconscious? - Yes.
-这会损伤他的那部分意识吗  -不会
- Are you destroying those parts of his mind? - No, no.
这些只是映射
They're just projections.
好了  我们到了
Okey. We are here.
暂时安全  抓紧时间  一整支军队正朝你们涌来
You are clear but hurry. There's an entire army heading your way.
进来了
We're in.
看这里
Look here!
-还有人在里面  -费舍  是陷阱  快出去
- Someone else's in there. - Fischer, it's a trap. Get out!
快啊  再下来点
Come on, a little lower.
柯布  不  她...
Cobb. No, she...
-她不是真的  -你怎么知道
- She is not real. - How do you know that?
她只是映射  费舍...费舍才是真的
She is just a projection. Fischer... Fischer is real.
你好
Hello.
伊姆斯  快去前厅
Eames! Eames! Get to the antechamber now!
-怎么回事  -茉儿把费舍杀了吗
- What happened? - Mal killed Fischer?
我下不了手
I couldn't shoot her.
他醒不过来了  他已经陷入了下一层
There's no use in reviving him, his mind's already trapped down there.
-都结束了  -就这样失败了吗
- It's all over. - So that's it? Then we failed?
完了  抱歉
We're done. I'm sorry.
回不了家的又不是我  是吧
Well, it's not me who doesn't get back to my family, is it?
真遗憾  我真想知道里面会发生什么
It's a shame. I really wanted to know what's gonna happen in there.
我肯定这次能成功
I swear we had this one.
装炸药吧
Let's set the charges.
等等  还有个方法
No, there's still another way.
-我们只要跟着费舍下去  -没时间了
- We just have to follow Fischer down there. - Not enough time.
不  进入下一层后就有足够时间
No, but there will... there will be enough time down there.
我们会找到他  好吗
And we will find him, okey?
亚瑟开始放音乐时
As soon as Arthur's music kicks in,
就用起搏器救活他
just use the defibrillator to revive him.
我们可以...在下层让他坠落回来
We can give him his... his own kick down below.
然后你让他进去
Look, you get him in there.
音乐一结束  就炸掉医院
As soon as the music ends, you blow up the hospital,
我们就能一起坠落回去了
and we all ride the kick back up the layers.
值得一试
That's worth a shot.
我布置炸药时  斋藤可以掩护我
Saito can hold the guards out, while I set the charges.
斋藤撑不了那么久吧
Saito will never make it, will he?
-柯布  我们必须试试  -行动吧
- Cobb, come on. We've got to try this. - Let's go.
你们要是没及时赶回来  我可不顾了你们了
If you are not back for the kick, I will go with or without you.
她说得没错  行动吧
She's right. She's right. Let's go.
我还能指望你完成接下来的任务吗
Can I trust you to do what needs to happen here?
我是说  茉儿也会在下面
I mean, Mal's gonna be down there.
我知道去哪找她  费舍肯定在她手里
I know where to find her. She'll have Fischer.
-你怎么知道  -因为...
- How do you know? - Because...
她想让我去下面找她
She wants me to come after her,
这样我们就能在一起了
she wants me back down there with her.
你没事吧
Are you alright?
-这就是你们的世界吗  -曾经是  她肯定在这
- This is your world? - Was. This is where she'll be.
走吧
Come on.
来
Come here.
斋藤
Saito, Saito!
你帮我保护好费舍
I need you, I need you to take care of Fischer,
我得去布置炸药  好吗
while I go set some charges. Okey?
这种工作可不能带观光客
No room for tourists on this job.
收回我的话
Who said?
这些都你们造的吗  太不可思议了
You built all this? This is incredible.
我们造了许多年
We built it for years.
记忆是我们的蓝图
And we started it on the memories.
这边
This way.
紧急制动
这是我们住的街区
This is our neighborhood,
照我们曾经的住处造的
The place is from our past.
那是我们的第一间公寓
That was our first apartment.
茉儿怀孕后  我们搬去了那栋房子
And we moved to that building right there, after Mal became pregnant,
之后就住在那儿
that became my home.
你们按记忆重建了这一切吗
You reconstructed all of this from memory?
跟你说过  我们有的是时间
Like I told you, we had lots of time.
-那是什么  -茉儿在那房子里长大
- What's that? - It's the house Mal grew up in.
-她会在里面吗  -不
- Will she be in there? - No.
来吧
Come on.
我们都想住那种别墅  但又钟爱高楼大厦
We both wanted to live in that house, but we loved this type of building.
在真实世界里  我们必须取舍  但在这不用
In the real world, we'd have to choose, but not here.
你准备怎么把费舍带回去
How would you bring Fischer back?
还是得想办法让他坠落
We have to come up with some kind of a kick.
-什么办法  -随机应变吧
- What? - We'd better improvise.
听着  你得了解我的一些事  关于植梦
Listen, there's something you should know about me, about inception.
想法就像病毒  顽强无比  感染性极强
An idea is like a virus, resilient, highly contagious.
再细微的念头也会生根发芽
A smallest seed of an idea can grow.
它能塑造你  也能毁灭你
It can grow to define or destroy you.
一个小小的念头  比如"你的世界不是真的"
The smallest idea such as "your world is not real,"
微不足道却改变了一切
Simple little thought that changes everything.
你是如此确信自己世界的真实
So certain of your world of what's real.
你觉得他可信吗
Do you think he is?
还是觉得其实他也像我一样迷失了
What do you think he is as lost as I was?
我能分得清真假虚实  茉儿
I know what's real, Mal.
从未心生疑虑吗
No creeping doubts,
也从没困扰过吗  道姆
not feeling persecuted, Dom?
满世界都有匿名组织和警察追捕你
Chased around the globe by anonymous corporations and police forces?
这难道不是映射追逐着梦主吗
Or whether the projections persecute the dreamer?
承认吧
Admit it,
你已不再相信所谓的现实
you don't believe in one reality anymore.
所以选择吧  选择留在这里
So choose, choose to be here,
选择陪着我
Choose me.
你知道我为何而来  我必须回到孩子身边
You know why I have the deal, have to get back to our children?
因为你抛弃了他们
Because you left them,
抛弃了我们
because you left us.
-你错了  -我没有
- You're wrong! - I'm not wrong.
你头脑混乱了
You're confused.
我们的孩子在这里
Our children are here.
你也想再看到他们的脸庞吧
And you'd like to see their faces again, wouldn't you?
没错  但要在现实的世界  茉儿
Yes. But I want to see them up above, Mal.
现实的世界
Up above?
听听你的心声
Listen to yourself.
他们就是我们的孩子
These are our children.
自己看
Watch.
詹姆斯  菲丽帕
James! Phillipa!
别这样  茉儿  求你了
Don't do this, Mal. Please.
他们不是我的孩子
Those aren't my children.
你一直这么告诫自己  但你并不相信
You keep telling yourself that, but you don't believe it.
-不  我确信  -如果你错了呢
- No, I know it! - What if you're wrong?
如果我才是真实的呢
What if I'm what's real?
你一直用自己的那套想法蒙蔽自己
You keep telling yourself what you know.
但你真正相信什么
But what do you believe?
又感觉到什么
What do you feel?
愧疚
Guilt.
我很愧疚  茉儿
I feel guilt, Mal.
不管我做什么  不管...
No matter what I do, no...
不管我是多么无助  多么困惑  那愧疚...
no matter how hopeless I am, no matter how I confused, that guilt...
都与我如影随形  让我无法忘怀真相
is always there, reminding me of the truth.
什么真相
What truth?
你对真实世界的质疑
That the idea that caused you to question your reality
全是因我而生
came from me.
你把这个想法植入了我的意识
You planted the idea in my mind?
她在说什么
What is she talking about?
我之所以确信植梦是可能的  是因为...
The reason I knew inception was possible was because I...
我对她植入过
I did it to her first.
-我曾对自己的妻子植梦  -为什么
- I did it to my own wife. - Why?
我们在这里迷失了
We were lost in here.
我清楚我们得逃离这一切  但她不愿接受
I knew we needed to escape, but she wouldn't accept it.
她把某些东西锁进了内心深处
She had locked something away, something.... something deep inside.
她曾经知晓的现实  她却选择将其遗忘
The truth that she had once known, but she chose to forget.
她深陷其中  无法自拔
She couldn't break free.
于是我决定去寻找它
So I decided to search for it,
走进她内心最深处  找到那秘密的角落
going deep into the recess of her mind and found that secret place.
我闯了进去
I broke in.
植入了一个想法
Then I planted an idea,
微不足道却改变了一切
a simple little idea that would change everything.
"她的世界不是真的"
That "her world wasn't real."
"死亡是唯一的解脱"
"the death was the only escape."
你在等待一列火车
You're waiting for a train,
那列火车将载你远去
The train that'll take you far away.
你了然自己心向何方
You know where you hope this train will take you,
却不知自己会被载往何处
But you can't know for sure.
但这并不重要
But it doesn't matter.
告诉我为什么
Now tell me why!
因为我们会在一起
Because we'll be together!
但我从未想到的是...
But I never knew that...
那个想法就像顽疾一般蔓延在她的脑海
that idea would grow in her mind like a cancer,
甚至在她梦醒后依旧不散
that even after she woke up.
甚至在你回归现实后依然耿耿于怀
That even after you came back to reality.
你依然相信  自己的世界不是真的
That you continue to believe your world wasn't real.
死亡是唯一的解脱
That death was the only escape.
茉儿  不要  老天爷啊...
Mal! No! Jesus...
-你侵入了我的意识  -我是想救你
- You infected my mind? - I was trying to save you.
你背叛了我
You betrayed me.
但你仍可以弥补  遵守你的诺言
But you can make amends, you can still keep your promise.
我们还能在一起
We can still be together,
就在这个我们一起创造的世界
right here, in the world we built together.
柯布  我们必须找到费舍
Cobb, we need to get Fischer.
你们找不到他
You can't have him.
-如果我留在这  能让他们走吗  -你说什么
- If I stay here, would you let them go? - What're you talking about?
费舍在门廊上
Fischer's on the porch.
-看看他还活着吗  -柯布  你不能这样
- Go check if he's alive. - Cobb, you can't do this.
快去看看他还活着吗  去吧
Go check if he's alive, right now. Do it.
柯布  他没事  时间到了  快来
Cobb, he's here. And it's time. You have to come now!
把费舍带走  好吗
Take Fischer with you, alright?
你不能留在这陪她
You can't stay here to be with her.
的确  斋藤此刻已经死了  他肯定在这里的某处
I'm not. Saito's dead by now, that means he's down here somewhere.
我必须找到他
It means I have to find him.
我不能再陪着她  因为她早已不复存在
I can't stay with her anymore, because she doesn't exist.
对你来说  我是唯一真实的存在
I'm the only thing you do believe in anymore.
是啊  我也想...
No. I wish...
我是多么地希望  但是...
I wish more than anything, but...
我想像不出你的复杂情绪
I can't imagine you with all your complexity,
你的种种完美和不完美
all your perfection, all your imperfection.
你还好吗
You alright?
看看吧
Look at you,
你只是个魅影
you're just a shade.
你只是我妻子的魅影
You're just the shade of my real wife.
我已经竭尽全力来想象了  但...
You're the best that I could do, but...
很遗憾  你远远比不上真实的她
I'm sorry, you are just not good enough.
这样感觉够真实了吧
Doesn't this feel real?
-你干什么  -随机应变
- What're you doing? - Improvise.
不  不  等等
No, no! No!
现在进去  快点  快去
Get in there, now. Go! Go, go, go!
罗伯特
Robert?
失...失...
Dis... disap...
-我很失...失...  -我明白  爸爸
- I was disa... disa... - I know, dad.
我明白你对我很失望  因为我成不了你
I know you were disappointed, I couldn't be you.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
我很失望...
I was disappointed...
因为你想成为另一个我
That you tried.
什么
What?
开启
遗嘱
该坠落了  艾莲涅  你快走
That's the kick, Ariadne! You have to go now!
别迷失了自己  找到斋藤  把他带回来
Don't lose yourself! Find Saito and bring him back!
我会的
I will!
记得你向我求婚那时吗
Do you remember when you asked me to marry you?
记得
Yes.
你说你梦到我们白头偕老
You said you dreamt that we grow old together.
我们做到了
But we did.
我们的确白头偕老了  不记得了吗
We did, you don't remember?
我想你想到无法呼吸  但是...
I miss you more than I can bear, but...
我们厮守了一生
we had our time together.
现在我必须放手了
I have to let you go.
放手让你安息
我很抱歉  罗伯特
I'm sorry, Robert.
爸爸是想通过遗嘱告诉我  要我走自己的路
You know, the will means that dad wanted me to be my own man.
不要仅仅是为他而活
Not just to live for him.
我决定就这么做  彼得叔叔
That's what I'm gonna do, uncle Peter.
-怎么回事  -柯布留在了那
- What happened? - Cobb stayed.
-和茉儿一起吗  -不  为了找到斋藤
- With Mal? - No, to find Saito.
他会迷失的
He'll be lost.
不  他会回来
No, he'll be alright.
你是来杀我的吗
Have you come to kill me?
我一直在等一个人
I'm waiting for someone,
他来自一个梦  而那个梦你已经记不清了
someone from a half remembered dream.
柯布
Cobb?
不可能
Impossible.
我们的年龄差不多
We were young men together.
而现在我已垂垂老矣
I'm an old man.
心中充满悔恨
Filled with regret.
孤零零地等死
Waiting to die alone, huh?
我回来找你
I've come back for you,
是为了提醒你...
to remind you...
一些事...
of something...
一些你曾知晓的事
something you once knew.
这个世界不是真的
That this world is not real.
来说服我履行我们之间的协议
To convince me to honor our arrangement.
没错  让你心怀幻想
To take a leap of faith, yes.
回去吧
Come back,
这样我们又能重回年轻
so we can be young men together again.
跟我回去吧
Come back with me.
回去吧
Come back.
先生  需要热毛巾吗
Hot towel, sir?
我们将在二十分钟内抵达洛杉矶
We will be landing in Los Angeles in about twenty minutes.
您需要入境申请表吗
Do you need immigration forms?
谢谢
Thank you.
-先生  需要热毛巾吗  -不了
- Hot towel, sir? - Oh, no.
您需要入境申请表吗
Do you need immigration forms?
欢迎回家  柯布先生
Welcome home, Mr. Cobb.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
这边
This way.
詹姆斯  菲丽帕
James? Philippa?
瞧瞧谁回来了
Look who's here.
-爸爸  爸爸  -孩子们  你们还好吗
- Daddy! Daddy! - Hey, kids! How are you?
-看我搭了什么  -你们玩什么呢
- Look what I built? - What're you doing there?
-我搭了一所悬崖上的小屋  -用石头搭的吗
- I built a house on the cliff. - Out of rocks?